<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>utf9k</title>
    <link>https://utf9k.net/tags/bookmarks/</link>
    <description>Posts from utf9k</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <author>
      <name>Marcus Crane</name>
      <email>marcus@utf9k.net</email>
    </author>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +1300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://utf9k.net/tags/bookmarks/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>My bookmarking categories in March 2020</title>
      <link>https://utf9k.net/blog/bookmarking-march-2020/</link>
      <description>A weird one off post where I documented the various bookmarks I had captured</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
      <author><name>Marcus Crane</name></author>
      <guid>https://utf9k.net/blog/bookmarking-march-2020/</guid>
      <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;For no particular reason, other than I figured it might help me make better sense of how I organise articles, here&amp;rsquo;s a fairly detailed breakdown of my bookmarking setup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently I&amp;rsquo;m using &lt;a href=&#34;https://raindrop.io&#34;&gt;Raindrop.io&lt;/a&gt; but I&amp;rsquo;ve also used &lt;a href=&#34;https://pinboard.in&#34;&gt;Pinboard&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://getpocket.com&#34;&gt;Pocket&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://larder.io&#34;&gt;Larder&lt;/a&gt; happily in the past too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the moment, Raindrop seems like the most comprehensive of the bookmarking apps I&amp;rsquo;ve tried. It has a very nice UI, a consistent desktop/mobile experience, a (newly launched) API and supports syncing content to a storage provider (Dropbox or Google Drive) too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I&amp;rsquo;ve linked some articles that I&amp;rsquo;ve found interesting myself within a lot of the categories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of them need some work, and I&amp;rsquo;ve got almost as many unsorted bookmarks as I do sorted since I write a custom title, description and apply tags for searching rather than just dumping them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had a lot of stuff from Pocket that I archived which makes up the bulk of it. Most things I had in Pinboard were tagged so they were easy to transition into Raindrop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;ve got any feedback or want to share your own bookmarking categories, let me know! You can find my contact details on my &lt;a href=&#34;https://utf9k.net/about&#34;&gt;about&lt;/a&gt; page B)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;heading&#34;&gt;???&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anything that is generally quirky or surprising like &lt;a href=&#34;https://audiokarma.org/forums/index.php?threads/jerry-seinfelds-speakers.48414/&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://cooking.stackexchange.com/questions/105602/steak-dropped-in-soapy-dish-water&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://oukosher.org/blog/industrial-kosher/peanut-butter-ii-standard-of-identity/&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;behind-the-scenes&#34;&gt;Behind the Scenes&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Great stories or posts that reveal what goes on behind the scenes of various products and companies&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=20908168&#34;&gt;Generally trends towards game development&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;business&#34;&gt;Business&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;economics&#34;&gt;Economics&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This tends to be anything related to the economy, &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Capitol_Hill_Babysitting_Co-op&#34;&gt;the theory of economics&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://abstrusegoose.com/389&#34;&gt;generally anything to do with money&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;marketing&#34;&gt;Marketing&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lessons and resources related to marketing of products, or marketing as an art&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;reports&#34;&gt;Reports&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Various reports (shareholder, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bankofengland.co.uk/-/media/boe/files/prudential-regulation/consultation-paper/2019/building-operational-resilience-impact-tolerances-for-important-business-services.pdf&#34;&gt;governmental&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://sriramk.com/memos/goldberg-music.pdf&#34;&gt;memos&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;resources&#34;&gt;Resources&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;General advice or reference material for going about conducting business and/or setting one up&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;strategy&#34;&gt;Strategy&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The art of &lt;a href=&#34;https://apenwarr.ca/log/20190926&#34;&gt;setting strategy&lt;/a&gt;, as it relates to business, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://danluu.com/sounds-easy/&#34;&gt;how business things get done, in spite of their sheer scale&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;design&#34;&gt;Design&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;inspiration&#34;&gt;Inspiration&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cool websites that have interesting designs in some form or another&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;resources-1&#34;&gt;Resources&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Design resources such as fonts, CSS frameworks, placeholder images or guides on how best to layout a design&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;ui--ux&#34;&gt;UI / UX&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tips and tricks on providing a functional, accessible design. Generally just for web design but doesn&amp;rsquo;t strictly have to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;miscellaneous&#34;&gt;Miscellaneous&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://digitalworldproblems.tumblr.com/post/76036641581/while-im-looking-at-that-moviecode-post-he&#34;&gt;Anything that doesn&amp;rsquo;t have an obvious category&lt;/a&gt;. If there seems to be a grouping of related articles, it&amp;rsquo;d prompt the creation of a new category but I also don&amp;rsquo;t want to generate more categories that are useful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;postmortems&#34;&gt;Postmortems&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Reviews in what went wrong, whether it be &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.propublica.org/article/the-red-cross-secret-disaster&#34;&gt;business&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.defmacro.org/2017/01/18/why-rethinkdb-failed.html&#34;&gt;software&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fudco.com/chip/lessons.html&#34;&gt;videogames&lt;/a&gt;. As this category grows, I&amp;rsquo;ll likely split them out into eg; Business/Postmortems but for now, I don&amp;rsquo;t have a big enough collection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;productivity&#34;&gt;Productivity&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anything related to the art of productivity. It may also just be &lt;a href=&#34;https://nesslabs.com/jomo&#34;&gt;articles reminding you that sometimes less is more!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;recommendations&#34;&gt;Recommendations&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Things that I have been recommended but haven&amp;rsquo;t looked into yet. If they are part of a medium that I track somewhere else (eg; books into Goodreads, games into How Long To Beat), then I tend to just put them there straight away. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.neogaf.com/threads/dead-franchises-almost-nobody-but-you-seems-to-want-back.1355948/&#34;&gt;There may be threads that have a wide range of recommendations&lt;/a&gt; eg; book recommendations so I generally scour them when I get time and put the interesting items into eg; Goodreads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;shopping&#34;&gt;Shopping&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Things that look cool and I might want to buy one day. I may also just want to keep them for reference to link to people too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;society&#34;&gt;Society&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;discourse&#34;&gt;Discourse&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A bit of a wishy washy grouping but anything related to discussion of ideas and &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/G._K._Chesterton#Chesterton.27s_fence&#34;&gt;what can go wrong as a result&lt;/a&gt;. Perhaps communication is a clearer name for this category.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;governments&#34;&gt;Governments&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Articles related to governments, whether it be their functions, warfare (from a political point of view, not an on-the-ground point of view) or just &lt;a href=&#34;https://web.archive.org/web/20071031080918/http://www.geocities.com/capecanaveral/4411/apollo13.htm&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;government related things&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;infrastructure&#34;&gt;Infrastructure&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This can be &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Signalling_System_No._7&#34;&gt;specific infrastructure&lt;/a&gt; or articles about infrastructure in general ie cost overruns or how a traffic light system operates&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;news-media&#34;&gt;News Media&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Resources provided by the news media (eg; a database containing financial entities and their appearances in the media) or articles about the media itself. This doesn&amp;rsquo;t contain articles FROM the news media however. It&amp;rsquo;s more of a meta category.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;people&#34;&gt;People&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This could be articles on &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Robert_Parker_(wine_critic)&#34;&gt;specific people&lt;/a&gt; (biographies, news pieces) or &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/scottlucas/san-francisco-spent-a-decade-being-rich-important-and&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;people&amp;rdquo; in a broader sense&lt;/a&gt; such as a story on a town or city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;politics&#34;&gt;Politics&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Politics of any form, whether it be governmental (elections, &amp;ldquo;red tape&amp;rdquo;) or more local such as office or industry politics&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;world-views&#34;&gt;World Views&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A bit of an abstract category. This contains articles and quotes that upon reading, I thought &lt;a href=&#34;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=14391552&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Oh! This gave me some insight into how certain groups or individuals come to view the world.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;. That&amp;rsquo;s neither a good or a bad thing, just interesting. Often it contains things that I&amp;rsquo;ve never considered before myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;sports&#34;&gt;Sports&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I had two links related to wrestling I put in here. I don&amp;rsquo;t follow sports much but sometimes there can be interesting crossovers between say sports and business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;technology&#34;&gt;Technology&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;databases&#34;&gt;Databases&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Articles, Stack Overflow snippets and links in general related to &amp;ldquo;databases&amp;rdquo;. For now, this has no subcategorisation between eg; MySQL v Postgres, SQL vs &amp;ldquo;NoSQL&amp;rdquo; and databases themselves vs database concepts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;growing-as-a-developer&#34;&gt;Growing As A Developer&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some recommendations from other developers (eg; keep a logbook), utilities (resume creators, competency matrixes) and other tools for improving as a developer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;historical-events&#34;&gt;Historical Events&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Links to &amp;ldquo;historical events&amp;rdquo; which can be anything from &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/npm/npm/issues/20791&#34;&gt;unexpected outages&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/facebook/react/issues/10191&#34;&gt;long running debates&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.doublewide.net/passport.htm&#34;&gt;fascinating snippets that somehow haven&amp;rsquo;t been lost yet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;languages&#34;&gt;Languages&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anything specific to a programming language whether it be a blog post, tutorial, library or book. At the moment, I haven&amp;rsquo;t split these out into subcategories as each article is tagged with their respective langauges anyway making search easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;lower-level&#34;&gt;Lower Level&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anything related to &amp;ldquo;low level things&amp;rdquo;. As someone who deals primarily with higher level languages (Python, Javascript) day to day, I classify C++ and C as low level too, haha.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;neighbours&#34;&gt;Neighbours&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is really just blog posts with no particular category or links to entire websites or blogs. Neighbours in this term just means other developers in the industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;networking&#34;&gt;Networking&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As it suggests on the tin, any articles, posts etc related to networking in general.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;observability&#34;&gt;Observability&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is a pretty new and empty category. I&amp;rsquo;m misusing the term on purpose as it has links to articles relating to observability as well as monitoring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;reference-materials&#34;&gt;Reference Materials&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anything (lists, lists of lists, books, websites etc) that are useful to reference. There are some things in here that shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be such as books on building applications in a specific language so it&amp;rsquo;s a little bit of a dumping ground at the moment. I don&amp;rsquo;t have a good distinction for where language-specific guides should live (languages or reference materials?)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;reverse-engineering&#34;&gt;Reverse Engineering&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;All things related to the art of reverse engineering such as applications, blog posts and reference guides&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;security&#34;&gt;Security&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As it says on the tin. Recommendations as well as &lt;a href=&#34;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/2669690/why-does-google-prepend-while1-to-their-json-responses&#34;&gt;interesting implementations&lt;/a&gt; related to security.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;shared-concepts&#34;&gt;Shared Concepts&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;If it&amp;rsquo;s technical / software development related but not part of any specific category (Unicode for example), I stick it in here&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-art-of-development&#34;&gt;The Art of Development&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is another wishy-washy category since it has some things which should be &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.pragmaticengineer.com/on-writing-well/&#34;&gt;part of Growing As A Developer&lt;/a&gt; as well as things that are more like &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.devever.net/~hl/xml&#34;&gt;how you should properly structure data&lt;/a&gt; rather than the actual act of development itself. I still need to refine this more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-industry-itself&#34;&gt;The Industry Itself&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This could be stories about &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bbsdocumentary.com/library/CONTROVERSY/LAWSUITS/SEA/katzbio.txt&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;people&amp;rdquo; (in an individual sense)&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hanselman.com/blog/DarkMatterDevelopersTheUnseen99.aspx&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;people&amp;rdquo; (in the group sense)&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://gigaom.com/2011/02/18/war-is-hell-welcome-to-the-twitter-wars-of-2011/&#34;&gt;people opposing other people&lt;/a&gt; and also &lt;a href=&#34;https://eager.io/blog/the-languages-which-almost-were-css/&#34;&gt;choices made by people&lt;/a&gt;. Sometimes companies too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;tooling&#34;&gt;Tooling&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tools and utilities that are useful to refer to later. Think CLIs, GUIs, CDNs and any other 3 letter combination you like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-art-of-writing&#34;&gt;The Art of Writing&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Something I&amp;rsquo;m looking to flesh out but any articles or references on how to write better!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
