<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>utf9k</title>
    <link>https://utf9k.net/tags/longterm/</link>
    <description>Posts from utf9k</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <author>
      <name>Marcus Crane</name>
      <email>marcus@utf9k.net</email>
    </author>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 19:00:00 +1300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://utf9k.net/tags/longterm/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>I don&#39;t identify as anxious</title>
      <link>https://utf9k.net/blog/i-dont-identify-as-anxious/</link>
      <description>Here are some things that have been bothering me</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 19:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
      <author><name>Marcus Crane</name></author>
      <guid>https://utf9k.net/blog/i-dont-identify-as-anxious/</guid>
      <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is my &lt;a href=&#34;https://apenwarr.ca/log/20171213&#34;&gt;epic treatise&lt;/a&gt; on the things that have been troubling me for some time now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like all of my most personal blog posts, you can expect this one to be at times flippant, absurd and other big words that I have to Google just to double check that I have the meaning correct.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Admittedly, I thought I had written something a bit closer to home, as far as mental health but it turns out that my &lt;a href=&#34;https://utf9k.net/blog/let-your-streaks-end-naturally&#34;&gt;previous attempts&lt;/a&gt; were much more abstract than I remember.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On some level, I write this for myself with the naive thought that I can capture all these feelings in a bottle and discard them, not unlike a &lt;a href=&#34;https://oxsci.org/can-a-camera-capture-your-soul/&#34;&gt;camera stealing a soul&lt;/a&gt;. Perhaps I&amp;rsquo;ll read this in future but really, I take some small comfort that perhaps this will be a useful barrier break for anyone who has a false idea of me in their head.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whatever I may have been able to live up to so far, this is hopefully proof enough that &amp;ldquo;success&amp;rdquo; by whatever means you define it is built on top of a great deal of well, whatever &lt;em&gt;this&lt;/em&gt; is, I don&amp;rsquo;t enjoy it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, that should be enough of a pretentious introduction to shoo away anyone with a short attention span.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of late, I have had a handful of panic attacks. I don&amp;rsquo;t think I use that word lightly. The feeling is that my entire body goes nuclear hot, where I&amp;rsquo;m borderline sweating. I might be shaking physically and usually I end up vomiting just due to the amount of nervous shaking upsets my stomach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s really not very nice! It kinda sucks!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This has only happened a few times in the past 6 months or so which is actually very rare but there&amp;rsquo;s a bit of a catch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From time to time, and today as I write this, I&amp;rsquo;ll catch myself remembering those feelings. It&amp;rsquo;s sort of like a mind virus. You can ever so slightly remember the feeling and then you can start to imagine yourself feeling it again. You feel a light flush. Oh no, it&amp;rsquo;s back isn&amp;rsquo;t it? It was always coming back. It was inevitable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are things that aren&amp;rsquo;t true but the trick that I am still learning is to quieten those voices. I don&amp;rsquo;t even think telling them to go away is the right approach. They&amp;rsquo;re all valid things that are worth accepting while pushing back on the idea that they are set in stone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It would perhaps be easy to &amp;ldquo;think positive&amp;rdquo; but so much of this all feels like it&amp;rsquo;s subconscious as far as I can tell. Perhaps it&amp;rsquo;s not but I just can&amp;rsquo;t hear the voice that is causing all this. How can I &amp;ldquo;win&amp;rdquo; a battle when I can&amp;rsquo;t even see the battlefield or my opponent. Well, again for the me 2 paragraphs ago, it isn&amp;rsquo;t a battle is it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These feelings are me and I am these feelings but I don&amp;rsquo;t have to lay down and let them run rampant. It&amp;rsquo;s easier to say that when you have a clear head.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps we should go over some specifics:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m 28 as I write this and I assume part of this stems from anxiety about turning 30. Turning 30 itself doesn&amp;rsquo;t scare me but there are all these little things in my head that I think I associate with having &amp;ldquo;made it&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Already this is stupid. I have a good paying job and I&amp;rsquo;m (allegedly) respected at work. I have minimal to no debt and I can toot my horn about having gone the hard route of not getting a degree. What does making it even mean? I have very little to genuinely worry about each day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got my restricted drivers license (Stage 2 of 3) when I was about 16 but I put off my final test so I haven&amp;rsquo;t driven for like 12 years. Part of me probably feels like I need to resolve all this so I can be self sufficient and all that. Successful people drive don&amp;rsquo;tcha know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m single but I&amp;rsquo;ve always been happy with my own company. Haven&amp;rsquo;t I? We had a lot of good times right? I never thought I minded but all of a sudden, it can get awfully lonely when you&amp;rsquo;re going through all this. It&amp;rsquo;s scary to live alone and you freak out at night. There&amp;rsquo;s no one around to talk to. Minutes can feel like hours and hours like weeks. Sleeping it all off would be a wonder except your body is primed to the brim with adrenaline so cross that off the list. I got a little teary writing this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can only imagine that these things are all in there somewhere contributing to this troubling period. You&amp;rsquo;ll be great and things are normal but suddenly you remember that you remember that you remember and it&amp;rsquo;s the darkest few hours of your waking existence. Why is this happening again? If I can just find the answer, will it leave me alone?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hardest answer, when I think over all the things that frighten me, is that I have to do all of this &lt;em&gt;waves hands&lt;/em&gt; for the next 70 years or more. I think that only to rebut myself in the same sentence with &amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s so bad about that? There are so many things to see and do!&amp;rdquo;. It&amp;rsquo;s the feeling of dread persisting at its core, I&amp;rsquo;m sure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not an anxious person? I don&amp;rsquo;t identify as such but factually, that might be correct? I don&amp;rsquo;t know, is it anxiety? It&amp;rsquo;s irrational for sure. It&amp;rsquo;s like I&amp;rsquo;m scared that I&amp;rsquo;m scared and I don&amp;rsquo;t know where it starts and ends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought I&amp;rsquo;d tackle it normally. I had some more severe bouts that were exponentially worse back when I wrote &lt;a href=&#34;https://utf9k.net/blog/ride-the-curve&#34;&gt;Ride the Curve&lt;/a&gt;. By all accounts, I&amp;rsquo;ve almost won, right? The symptoms are a whisper of what they were and the distance between them is ever shorter but when it pops up, I just want to give up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps I&amp;rsquo;ll ask my doctor if I can go back to &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Escitalopram&#34;&gt;what helped break me out last time&lt;/a&gt;. I don&amp;rsquo;t take any pride in fighting mental illness on hard mode. I don&amp;rsquo;t wish it on anyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I dunno, I&amp;rsquo;ll go about my day and things are great. Great is a strong word. Things are fine. Maybe I need more novelty in my life. It&amp;rsquo;s the remmebering that this whole ordeal exists that opens the door ever so slightly for doubt to creep in. It could happen again so why wouldn&amp;rsquo;t it, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been even stronger in reassuring myself that there are so many possibilities and that it&amp;rsquo;s just my brain playing tricks but it&amp;rsquo;s exhausting. Trying to self-monitor your own thoughts is exhausting. Your brain is effectively playing dual roles where you&amp;rsquo;re watching yourself in third person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Writing this has made me go up and down a bit where I&amp;rsquo;m a little jittery but who knows, that could just be the cold that&amp;rsquo;s creeping in and I&amp;rsquo;m unintentionally feeding the nuclear fire with all these inputs that are unrelated. While things are quiet, I think I&amp;rsquo;ll go to bed early. Napping is great. I wish I had more time this afternoon but I don&amp;rsquo;t want to risk staying up. A thought creeped in that today was going to be one of the very bad ones. Let&amp;rsquo;s hope it isn&amp;rsquo;t true.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you read this far, I appreciate the effort. I&amp;rsquo;m sure I&amp;rsquo;ll be fine in the long run. While all these emotions were fresh, I wanted to capture them down since they&amp;rsquo;re hard to explain. I don&amp;rsquo;t even know if any of this makes sense since I write these sorts of posts off the cuff with no editing.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let your streaks end naturally</title>
      <link>https://utf9k.net/blog/let-your-streaks-end-naturally/</link>
      <description>As it says on the tin, all good things must come to an end</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 12:50:00 +1300</pubDate>
      <author><name>Marcus Crane</name></author>
      <guid>https://utf9k.net/blog/let-your-streaks-end-naturally/</guid>
      <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Generally speaking, it&amp;rsquo;s always a good idea to let your streaks end when the time is right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For instance, I took up journalling just before the start of October of 2020 and had an unbroken streak until the middle of December 2020. I picked it up again in the middle of January and it ran all the way until the start of June when I had a particularly troubling &lt;a href=&#34;https://utf9k.net/blog/ride-the-curve/&#34;&gt;life event&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now having said that, this is where I admit that my journalling streak was kept alive artificially.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t actually fill out each entry on each given day but instead, I would forget about it and backfill days (or even a week!) at a time. At that point, it should have become clear that the act of journalling, in and of itself, wasn&amp;rsquo;t compelling enough to keep me interested.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I sit back and think about it, it&amp;rsquo;s probably fair to say that I was more invested in the aesthetics of keeping a journal more than the journal itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dayoneapp.com/&#34;&gt;Day One&lt;/a&gt; has a cool feature for &lt;a href=&#34;https://help.dayoneapp.com/en/articles/769055-book-printing&#34;&gt;printing books&lt;/a&gt; and the idea of having a coffee table book&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; was very cool but these are all side effects of journaling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m sure it&amp;rsquo;s ok to pursue a habit as a means to the actual thing you want to achieve but just as long as you&amp;rsquo;re aware of the potential pitfalls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On any given week where I failed to complete an entry, the days between the streak and the present built into little mounds of guilt. Nothing bad mind you but just enough to think &amp;ldquo;I need to backfill this entire week&amp;rdquo; to keep the streak going. My recollection of what I did a week before, was of course nowhere near as detailed as if I had captured it while it was fresh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most importantly, while the streak icon was burning brightly, I was well aware in my mind that the flame had gone out long ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I resolved to only fill in a journal entry if I naturally felt compelled to, it was actually quite freeing. I didn&amp;rsquo;t have to think about the artificial guilt that comes with completionism&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Funnily enough, some things I haven&amp;rsquo;t decided to explicitly grow a streak in, such as reviewing &lt;a href=&#34;https://readwise.io&#34;&gt;Readwise&lt;/a&gt; bookmarks, have since developed into their own streaks naturally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m sure these too will end too when the time is right and that&amp;rsquo;s completely fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps you could say the same of relationships too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--- Written with A.I in mind --&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not that I actually have a coffee table, or lounge, mind you!&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A riduculous idea of course, since I&amp;rsquo;m missing journal entries ranging from my birth to my 25th birthday. There&amp;rsquo;s literally no way anyone can ever &amp;ldquo;complete&amp;rdquo; a journal or backfill the pages.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ride the curve</title>
      <link>https://utf9k.net/blog/ride-the-curve/</link>
      <description>A post from a darker time on how to better think about taking a break</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 May 2021 10:40:00 +1300</pubDate>
      <author><name>Marcus Crane</name></author>
      <guid>https://utf9k.net/blog/ride-the-curve/</guid>
      <content type="html">&lt;div class=&#34;notice&#34;&gt;
  &lt;hr class=&#34;hidden&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;h3&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;🚣‍♀️&lt;/span&gt;It&amp;#39;s rough seas out there!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not so long ago, I was struggling with instances of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Depersonalization&#34;&gt;something very unfamiliar&lt;/a&gt; , which scared the shit out of me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As one of many distractions, I popped open a text editor and started writing about my life so far and this is what came out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve strongly resisted the urge to make any edits, beyond adding links for context. All footnotes were already written inline with the draft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t fully reread it nor do I really intend to. I also never got to the actual point of the title, which is what I started off with as a prompt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short, I&amp;rsquo;m trying to relax more and look after myself. That doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean stopping work but riding the momentum I already built up, whether I realise it or not.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;hr class=&#34;hidden&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generally, I tend to worry a lot about what things might look like in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If it all turns to custard, will I have transferrable skills that are sought after?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My tendency is to frame the tech industry as a sort of gold rush that sooner or later will dry up. I imagine that maybe it will hit market saturation or be dismissed due to intense distrust thanks to key/buzzwords like Surveillance and Algorithms that always seem poised to spiral out of control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;del&gt;some&lt;/del&gt; most ways, this is a ridiculous thing to worry about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly because an industry that can service other industries (see: accounting, consulting, compliance etc) rarely run out of business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secondly, most things are cyclical so a crash here will peak once again over there. We only have to look at various bubbles and crashes (see: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dot-com_bubble&#34;&gt;the dotcom boom&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Financial_crisis_of_2007%E2%80%932008&#34;&gt;Global Financial Crisis&lt;/a&gt; or even the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/COVID-19_recession&#34;&gt;Coronavirus Pandemic&lt;/a&gt; which is still ongoing)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, the final and true answer is that no one can know the future. We can predict things, often with some accuracy but us humans are unpredictable so even sane assumptions can fall apart in an instant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;abandoning-ship&#34;&gt;Abandoning ship&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I was towards the end of my teenage years (I&amp;rsquo;m only 26!), I figured I had missed the boat when it came to &amp;ldquo;Computer Science&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I liked messing around with web pages and I thought the internet was fascinating despite only having a vague understanding of how it worked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember trawling through forum posts for MMOs and absolutely loving the technical explanations of why Final Fantasy 14 developers &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/ffxiv/comments/6h4129/yoshida_acknowledging_glamour_importance/divdh85/&#34;&gt;struggled to allocate more bag slots&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://forum.square-enix.com/ffxiv/threads/125277-Triple-Monitor-Display?p=1631847&amp;amp;highlight=Minagawa#post1631847&#34;&gt;the troubles with aspects&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite all this, and years of trawling &lt;a href=&#34;https://news.ycombinator.com&#34;&gt;Hacker News&lt;/a&gt; daily which built up a fairly solid vocabulary, I never actually properly started programming until what I thought was quite late.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I considered myself a hobbyist and had dabbled in a bit of Python but I didn&amp;rsquo;t &amp;ldquo;get&amp;rdquo; any of it for a long time, probably since I didn&amp;rsquo;t have a mental model to hang any of it in a useful way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I distinctly remember &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bbc.com/news/technology-34066941&#34;&gt;some BBC article came out ranking the likelihood of job automation&lt;/a&gt; had came out in my third year of retail. It listed retail workers as having something like a 97% chance of being automated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nowadays, I think back on that and find it kind of funny. Due in part to being a technical hobbyist, I would daydream about automating parts of my job and thinking about how inefficient the systems seemed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Probably for that reason, I thought I could &amp;ldquo;feel&amp;rdquo; it coming, like a rising tide that would swallow me up and that fear was a useful, although probably not healthy motivator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Between that fear and a general sense of worthlessness and disappointment, I decided to throw my eggs in one basket and attend a web development bootcamp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m sure for some, it was just a brief chance to dabble in a profession to see if they&amp;rsquo;re interested but for me, at that time, I felt it was my last chance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saddled with the idea of spending the next 50+ years, pushing shopping carts and being derailed into conversations that amounted to &amp;ldquo;What if the store just simply made everything more efficient&amp;rdquo; for the 600th time, I honestly did not expect to live this long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, as for how I came up with the funding: Doing a lot of saving coupled with a bank loan for a &amp;ldquo;cruise to Japan&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;actually-finding-a-job&#34;&gt;Actually finding a job&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Going to &lt;a href=&#34;https://devacademy.co.nz/&#34;&gt;a bootcamp&lt;/a&gt; was a step in the right direction and a chance to understand the industry but I will never claim you can attend one and instantly become a fully fledged developer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plenty of people were lucky and found side jobs or internships relatively quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was arguably unlucky in that I persisted for an extra year on minimal savings and spent what felt like the majority of every day pouring over crap, building side projects and doing tutorials, filling out job applications and probably trying to not cry a lot of the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a side note, a man in his 40s or so moved into our flat at one point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first, he seemed fine but progressively shared some conspiratorial views until I found out he was literally a white supremacist. I&amp;rsquo;m not misusing the term literally here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of his friends once talked about beating me to death while I was in my room, with the lights of, pretending to be out of the house.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This inspired me to learn how to set up a &lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.com/&#34;&gt;Discord&lt;/a&gt; bot that would poll our router for connected devices and I could query to see if I felt safe to come home. Odds are, if he was home, he was in the lounge and would say Hello and draw me into a two hour, mostly one sided conversation where I would nod and say &amp;ldquo;H-hah, sure, I guess the UN could be trying to control the population&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In hindsight, I was probably pretty stressed during that time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;working-to-keep-working&#34;&gt;Working to keep working&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;With going into too much detail, I had the good fortune to work at one of New Zealand&amp;rsquo;s largest tech companies and at present, I work for one of the largest car companies. Ironic, given I don&amp;rsquo;t drive.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite all that, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if I relax enough. Actually, I&amp;rsquo;m not even sure if I know what that is exactly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, I&amp;rsquo;m not a robot and unfortunately I&amp;rsquo;m not a machine either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like playing videogames but I&amp;rsquo;d dropped off a lot since I started working. Last year, I even got annoyed that I didn&amp;rsquo;t game very much so I sold my gaming desktop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I figured I&amp;rsquo;d double down on research and what not and try to do more productive things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is probably near enough the root of my troubles and why I&amp;rsquo;m writing it all down today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think I still have that driving fear that I&amp;rsquo;ll be made redundant one day. I probably will and that&amp;rsquo;s perfectly fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s nowhere near strong enough as it was back then when it felt like a choice between life and death but it&amp;rsquo;s still enough to make me hesitate between reading a book and playing a game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps I overcorrected a lot. I like the idea that a to do list is better framed as a &amp;ldquo;things i could do&amp;rdquo; list since that sums it up nicely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s easy to imagine side projects and then see them tower up. More and more until you realise you could never achieve these in your lifetime. The mere thought of them becomes exhausting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thankfully my blog isn&amp;rsquo;t quite like that. I have a couple of small goals buried somewhere but I don&amp;rsquo;t feel bad about not posting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the most part, I just imagine no one reads this anyway. I heard once from a reader which was really cool and sometimes I peek at analytics to see a lot of people seem to get value from &lt;a href=&#34;https://utf9k.net/blog/wsl2-vhd-issue/&#34;&gt;my Windows 10 VHD post&lt;/a&gt;. Beyond those technical things, I struggle to imagine anyone investing time into these.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;whats-next&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s next?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I had been meaning to write a post about my intentions with my blog. I&amp;rsquo;m still active and I have things on my list but mostly it feels like something driven by guilt and fear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A portfolio to say that I existed but not one with enough value to actually act as a portfolio!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My intention going forward is to encourage myself to post a bit more often but with less lengthy content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Things that I find interesting and are worth sharing as well as a few larger, &amp;ldquo;original&amp;rdquo; posts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve got one that I&amp;rsquo;m particularly excited to get struck into that&amp;rsquo;s a little quirky and is a bit of a fun investigation story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I run into technical troubles from time to time and I&amp;rsquo;ll generally still share those but they don&amp;rsquo;t really come up often and admittedly, I don&amp;rsquo;t find them hugely interesting unless some sort of a story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve also changed the structure of the site a little bit. You can see any drafts at &lt;a href=&#34;https://next.utf9k.net&#34;&gt;next.utf9k.net&lt;/a&gt; and I manually merge things into the live branch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given that there&amp;rsquo;s a concept of &amp;ldquo;staging&amp;rdquo; where I can add things piecemeal, I might start managing longer posts as Github issues where I can make notes to myself and sort of &amp;ldquo;work out in the open&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean a story in the open is guaranteed to happen but adds a little bit more structure that might help with stories that are otherwise a bit overwhelming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My tendency is to write them all in one sitting (like this post) with an optional review but it&amp;rsquo;s probably a bit healthier to piece things out and not potentially feel so overwhelmed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;beyond-the-site&#34;&gt;Beyond the site&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Of course, this was just an excuse to shoe horn in some thoughts about this site into an otherwise fairly personal post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t feel that I&amp;rsquo;ve ever really shied away from talking about my feelings very much so I don&amp;rsquo;t consider sharing this to be a huge effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having said that, maybe there&amp;rsquo;s some value for other people in reading these sorts of things?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m sure others can relate when I say I feel a bit paradoxical about a lot of things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, the idea of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fear_of_missing_out&#34;&gt;FOMO&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/01/26/business/against-hustle-culture-rise-and-grind-tgim.html&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Hustle culture&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; is stupid and unhealthy, yet at the same time I&amp;rsquo;ve clearly just described what is basically someone who struggles to ignore it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t feel like I have to do anything but at the same time, I get a bit itchy when I&amp;rsquo;m away from something constructive for too long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think I would actually hate the idea of being retired on a beach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would like to be retired with &lt;a href=&#34;https://howlongtobeat.com/user/Sentry&#34;&gt;my videogame backlog&lt;/a&gt; however.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve got some personal (and mental) struggles to deal with and perhaps I&amp;rsquo;ll share some of those.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I gotta head off now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until next time, happy travels!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MMO developers seem to have a tendency to be more open than most, probably because subscriptions from the fans directly keep them going rather than publisher deals.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have my restricted license but my flat is quite literally on a main road so we don&amp;rsquo;t have any place to park.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
