<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>utf9k</title>
    <link>https://utf9k.net/tags/business/</link>
    <description>Posts from utf9k</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <author>
      <name>Marcus Crane</name>
      <email>marcus@utf9k.net</email>
    </author>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 23:12:00 +1300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://utf9k.net/tags/business/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Remind the user what your service does</title>
      <link>https://utf9k.net/blog/remind-the-user-what-your-service-does/</link>
      <description>You haven&#39;t emailed me for 2 years! Who are you again?</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 23:12:00 +1300</pubDate>
      <author><name>Marcus Crane</name></author>
      <guid>https://utf9k.net/blog/remind-the-user-what-your-service-does/</guid>
      <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This goes out to anyone who does marketing for startups and businesses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re about to announce something like an update for those on a waitlist or a big bang version 2, please include a reminder of what your service actually is?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;rsquo;t count the number of times I receive an email out of the blue saying &amp;ldquo;Smergen is nearly here!&amp;rdquo; only for me to scratch my head out of confusion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A decent improvement is to just include screenshots (but not those vague &amp;ldquo;big tech art&amp;rdquo; things, real ones!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The actual fix is just to include a one liner like &amp;ldquo;Smergen - the app that lets you map public toilets&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To really drive it home, here&amp;rsquo;s a masterclass in retaining the user from &lt;a href=&#34;https://nvultra.com&#34;&gt;nvUltra&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;nvultra.png&#34; alt=&#34;An email snippet from nvUltra explaning how they have been infrequent with updates and then providing a detailed reminder on what nvUltra actually is, in simple english.&#34;  /&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you can&amp;rsquo;t take a few seconds to provide some context for what your announcement is about, I can&amp;rsquo;t get excited or even bring myself to care.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You can always count on sales</title>
      <link>https://utf9k.net/blog/you-can-always-count-on-sales/</link>
      <description>Complete system downtime won&#39;t stop the sales team from making a buck</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 18:23:00 +1300</pubDate>
      <author><name>Marcus Crane</name></author>
      <guid>https://utf9k.net/blog/you-can-always-count-on-sales/</guid>
      <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;For any readers who weren&amp;rsquo;t aware, &lt;a href=&#34;https://status.azure.com&#34;&gt;Microsoft Azure&lt;/a&gt; suffered from a &lt;a href=&#34;https://rcpmag.com/articles/2021/03/16/what-happened-azure-ad-outage.aspx&#34;&gt;major Azure Active Directory outage&lt;/a&gt; back in March 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A great deal of services were degraded while I was at work so I mostly spent March 15th, 2021 monitoring the situation and broadcasting status updates for fellow affected teams internally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the updates were just synthesised from Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s various Twitter accounts which happened to be more up to date than the public status pages, but that&amp;rsquo;s a story for another blog post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Towards the end of the day, it got me wondering how widely Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s own services were affected by this outage. I mean, they dogfood their product offerings after all, right? Apparently Sales doesn&amp;rsquo;t, at least for any incoming enquiries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you go to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/services/active-directory/&#34;&gt;marketing site for Azure Active Directory&lt;/a&gt;, you may notice a little &amp;ldquo;Chat with Sales&amp;rdquo; tab appear in the bottom right hand corner after all of the various scripts have loaded in the background.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clicking on that tab reveals an &lt;a href=&#34;https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/services/bot-services/&#34;&gt;Azure Chatbot&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;ll ask you which type of help you&amp;rsquo;d like and then you can select one of the follow categories:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Technical support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Business support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sales&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I captured some footage following the dialogue path of these three options during the ongoing Azure AD outage so let&amp;rsquo;s see what happens when selecting each of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;technical-support&#34;&gt;Technical Support&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;You might imagine that this would be the most important option when it comes to resiliency during any major outages. Of course, if you&amp;rsquo;re an enterprise then you should really have an enterprise support plan but if you&amp;rsquo;re a startup or an indie, this might be well outside your budget.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;video style=&#34;display: inherit; margin: 0 auto;&#34; width=&#34;50%&#34; controls&gt;
&lt;source preload src=&#34;01-technical.mp4&#34; type=&#34;video/mp4&#34;&gt;
Ah, sorry! It looks like your browser either hates the h264 codec or it just doesn&#39;t support the video tag.
&lt;/video&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hmm, I don&amp;rsquo;t know about you but it looked like nothing happened and our request just disappeared into the ether!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;business-support&#34;&gt;Business Support&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now surely if a technical person can&amp;rsquo;t get through, business support is much more likely to make it. Nothing says importance like an executive with a credit card after all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;video style=&#34;display: inherit; margin: 0 auto;&#34; width=&#34;50%&#34; controls&gt;
&lt;source preload src=&#34;02-business.mp4&#34; type=&#34;video/mp4&#34;&gt;
Ah, sorry! It looks like your browser either hates the h264 codec or it just doesn&#39;t support the video tag.
&lt;/video&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No dice, basically the same exact outcome. I expected better! Pssh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;sales&#34;&gt;Sales&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now we know for sure that Sales isn&amp;rsquo;t going to work if the former two aren&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In any sane business, all attention should be directed towards supporting paying customers and alleviating any of their concerns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;d be ridiculous to focus on some potentially unrealised future revenues!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;video style=&#34;display: inherit; margin: 0 auto;&#34; width=&#34;50%&#34; controls&gt;
&lt;source preload src=&#34;03-sales.mp4&#34; type=&#34;video/mp4&#34;&gt;
Ah, sorry! It looks like your browser either hates the h264 codec or it just doesn&#39;t support the video tag.
&lt;/video&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hmm, perhaps I was wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-it-supposed-to-look-like&#34;&gt;What is it supposed to look like?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I actually went through this same dialog flow, now two months down the track, and I was under the impression that all three options put you into a live call.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems that both Technical and Business Support options simply redirect you to &lt;a href=&#34;https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/support/create-ticket/&#34;&gt;submit a support ticket&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That makes sense but it also begs the question &amp;ldquo;How was this unavailable?&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presumably the bot is querying for the support ticket URL in some backend every time you click on the button or something equally unnecessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had a quick poke around the acres of websocket events using the developer tools in my browser but there are like 5 events fired off just from clicking a button. It seemed like it was going to be a mess to dig through so I didn&amp;rsquo;t even bother.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, there&amp;rsquo;s an old adage that&amp;rsquo;s probably relevant here. I don&amp;rsquo;t actually know how it goes but basically, if you ever need to get a hold of someone at a company, just call the Sales department because they always pick up the phone.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Relying on the internet as a business</title>
      <link>https://utf9k.net/blog/internet-reliance/</link>
      <description>It&#39;s wild that you can couple a physical business to digital technology to the extent that one can&#39;t operate without the other</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
      <author><name>Marcus Crane</name></author>
      <guid>https://utf9k.net/blog/internet-reliance/</guid>
      <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I went to get a haircut about 45 minutes before writing this post, and the internet went out briefly. I overheard one of the hair stylists say&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s weird to think how much we rely on the internet, huh?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clearly, this isn&amp;rsquo;t a new thought, and this post is being made up as I write it but it&amp;rsquo;s always an interesting thought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, the first thing I heard when I walked in the door was &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ll be with you in 2 seconds, the internet has just gone out&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be quite clear, I like the hair stylist I go to. I hate haircuts so any observations are just that but naturally, I thought&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does that have to do with haircuts&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought about it a bit while I was there and realised it must be quite hard to be a non-technical business owner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For starters, when the internet &amp;ldquo;goes out&amp;rdquo;, all sorts of things start breaking of course. You can&amp;rsquo;t reach your booking system. Perhaps people are booking still, and some managed service is confirming them automatically, but you have no visibility into your expected workflow for later that day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re also not really giving proper attention to the people presently there either, since it&amp;rsquo;s in the back of your mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re non-technical after all, you don&amp;rsquo;t really have a mental model of all of the devices in your building and how many of them depend on ethernet or a wireless access point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mean, maybe you know roughly what does of course but there&amp;rsquo;s plenty of things that are easy to get about since they… always just work?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There wasn&amp;rsquo;t actually any music, or rather it stopped playing at one point. Personally, I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have noticed but lo and behold, Spotify does indeed require the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They have mobile EFTPOS terminals that have no cables too so I wonder if they&amp;rsquo;re running off of WiFi too. That makes them about as useful as a brick without those juicy packets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, this post is partly me trying to sort through my spaghetti thoughts and I think there were two main things that popped into my head:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a business owner, just how many dependencies do you end up with that you don&amp;rsquo;t properly understand?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wonder to what extent, slowly over time, you get introduced to the cooler, mobile EFTPOS terminal. Don&amp;rsquo;t be tied down with all those cables, you could be trendy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok, ok, I&amp;rsquo;m being heavily sarcastic, no one actually drops however much on a whim for non-essentials but with the rise in internet-connected &amp;ldquo;things&amp;rdquo;, perhaps there ends up being an unavoidable Ship of Theseus type effect where one day, your entire business can be closed for the day if the internet goes out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even for business that seemingly have no real essential need for the internet, but get convinced about some cool new online booking system or whatever. I can imagine as &amp;ldquo;internet&amp;rdquo; niches dry up over time, ever more businesses will be convinced to dive into technology in order to create new niches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The booking system that the hair stylist I used is some basic bootstrap thing with some dropdowns yet there&amp;rsquo;s an entire business that makes &amp;ldquo;premium hair salon booking systems&amp;rdquo;. Perhaps the wildest part is that time is the bottleneck here, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Surely booking can&amp;rsquo;t physically be any more complex than it was as a kid, when staff had paper-based agendas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this case, I&amp;rsquo;m just talking about places with a comparable number of staff of course. You&amp;rsquo;d want something a bit more scalable with tens or hundreds of staff but until we get hair stylists that rent out a warehouse for some sort of olympic hairdressing event, the problem space seems about the same to me as it ever did. What&amp;rsquo;s the problem we solved here exactly?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point I&amp;rsquo;m just ranting about technology but this does bring me around to my second question:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is there, or should there be, such a thing as technology risk assessment/dependency modelling for businesses?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This goes back to the mention of mental models but for your average business owner, I imagine you might not really understand that technology isn&amp;rsquo;t a monolith? You&amp;rsquo;ve got disciplines ranging from wild west code slinging to &amp;ldquo;Just wrapped up a 7 month design trip visiting the wetlands of Croatia&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bootstrap is fine, I don&amp;rsquo;t hate Javascript for keeping me hostage and Zuck can grill meats all he wants but I know for sure when I look at a barebones booking system and wonder &amp;ldquo;So what do they do all day? This seems like a grad project&amp;rdquo;, their customers most likely don&amp;rsquo;t have the same point of view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taste in design isn&amp;rsquo;t really a concern here but I can&amp;rsquo;t help but wish there was some sort of crash course where people could work through hypotheticals like the above situation I described.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not really sure what to say here other than you can&amp;rsquo;t really avoid engineering a single point of failure if you don&amp;rsquo;t even know what that is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, if I was trying to run a business and focus on &amp;ldquo;what actually matters&amp;rdquo;, I&amp;rsquo;d probably just think &amp;ldquo;Sounds boring/complicated/nerd crap&amp;rdquo; which is ironic given, you know, I&amp;rsquo;m writing this post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Realistically, none of this matters. No one else noticed, or even cared, especially not enough to spend their entire lunch break writing over 70 something lines on hair styling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s perhaps something more to think about and I probably shouldn&amp;rsquo;t publish this given how it&amp;rsquo;s kind of half baked but maybe it&amp;rsquo;ll inspire you to write something actionable and coherent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personally, I think if we still had 3.5mm jacks, I could have just streamed Spotify via mobile for them until the internet came back on. How&amp;rsquo;s that for collective action?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
