<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>utf9k</title>
    <link>https://utf9k.net/tags/money/</link>
    <description>Posts from utf9k</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <author>
      <name>Marcus Crane</name>
      <email>marcus@utf9k.net</email>
    </author>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 23:40:00 +1300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://utf9k.net/tags/money/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing subscriptions with an extra debit card</title>
      <link>https://utf9k.net/blog/subscription-management/</link>
      <description>In which I save myself from financial hell by putting subscriptions on another card where they can&#39;t creep up on me</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 23:40:00 +1300</pubDate>
      <author><name>Marcus Crane</name></author>
      <guid>https://utf9k.net/blog/subscription-management/</guid>
      <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The title says it all really but I&amp;rsquo;ll go into detail a little more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the handiest tricks I ever discovered earlier last year, was to get a second debit card issued specifically just for subscriptions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not so long ago, I used to just have my primary account tied to my debit card, and a couple of others that weren&amp;rsquo;t accessible through any physical means.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few times, I would get a bit too eager to try out subscription services and slowly, my primary account would get eaten. Similarly, surprise yearly renewals would suddenly eat a portion of my bank account to my horror.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My &amp;ldquo;fix&amp;rdquo; for this was to transfer all of my money instantly out of my primary account and across to another savings account. I&amp;rsquo;d keep a minimal amount on my card and perform transfers on the fly as I needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This actually caused me a lot of grief once when I was trying to check into a hotel while visiting America. My bank actually had maintenance on their mobile app so I was stuck with just shy of the required bank deposit and no way to access any of my money. Thankfully, the clerk let me pay it in the morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It got particularly bad when I joined a gym. They would do their debit charges on a Friday but I swear it never felt consistent. Sometimes it would be on a Saturday or it would be first thing Friday morning. More than a few times, I forgot or be late, causing both the charge to decline and myself to pay a dishonour fee as I didn&amp;rsquo;t have enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, at this point, you may think that I should have been more vigilant in transfering across the required amount which brings us full circle. Sometimes I would perform a transfer for the required amount the night before&amp;hellip; only for a subscription renewal to eat into the balance, causing a decline because what the heck, suddenly I don&amp;rsquo;t have enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, it occured to me that when you break it down, there are two streams of charges: those that are controlled (ie I physically swipe my card) and those that I would call erratic. The latter are often a known quantity but soetimes they&amp;rsquo;re a moving target, sometimes my dumb human brain forgets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the most part, the feeling is that of being inside of an interrogation room. That is to say, there&amp;rsquo;s a kind of one way mirror where I don&amp;rsquo;t really know what could jump out at any minute and eat my wallet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So anyway, what I did was requested a second debit card that I use entirely just for subscriptions and the like. I don&amp;rsquo;t do anything fancy, just roughly eyeball how much is expected to go out based on last month and transfer it in. Every week or so I&amp;rsquo;ll move amounts in and out based on how close to the mark I&amp;rsquo;ve been.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A very handy side effect is that you&amp;rsquo;ve also got a clear view into your recurring expenses. Often times you can forget you&amp;rsquo;re subscribed to something for a long time because the transactions are buried amongst your life stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With your subscription only bank account, you&amp;rsquo;ve got a continuous feed of things you&amp;rsquo;re subscribed to and hey, you didn&amp;rsquo;t even need to pay a SaaS company to figure it out!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
