<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>utf9k</title>
    <link>https://utf9k.net/tags/rambling/</link>
    <description>Posts from utf9k</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <author>
      <name>Marcus Crane</name>
      <email>marcus@utf9k.net</email>
    </author>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +1300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://utf9k.net/tags/rambling/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Quicksand</title>
      <link>https://utf9k.net/blog/quicksand/</link>
      <description>Being stuck in place, or believing that you are at least, is not fun</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
      <author><name>Marcus Crane</name></author>
      <guid>https://utf9k.net/blog/quicksand/</guid>
      <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I think one of the worst feelings is that of being stuck in quicksand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not literally but in the sense that you&amp;rsquo;re just reacting to things. It gets exhausting and then you&amp;rsquo;re suddenly lagging behind a little bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given you&amp;rsquo;re already starting each day at a deficit, it feels like you&amp;rsquo;re now in a race to get back to normal. That is, being on top of everything, planning ahead and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess it&amp;rsquo;s just noticing the gap between where you&amp;rsquo;re at, and where you could be but that in itself can be stressful. More so than any actual task or project on your plate even.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There could be a word for it but I usually just refer to it as quicksand because it feels like the more you stuggle, the more tired you get and the deeper you sink.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether it&amp;rsquo;s work or side projects, it becomes tempting to spend even more of your personal time ironing those out so you can get back to square one but it never really seems to happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Usually that&amp;rsquo;s a pretty good sign that you&amp;rsquo;re doing too much stuff that you really don&amp;rsquo;t need to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the case of side projects, or all the things you &amp;ldquo;wish&amp;rdquo; you were doing but never seem to find the time, it might be a sign that you&amp;rsquo;ve got stuff on your backlog that you don&amp;rsquo;t really care about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I were to look in my projects file right now, at least half of them are things that I haven&amp;rsquo;t started and looking back, I don&amp;rsquo;t really care to do them but feel like I should.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the case of work, I think I just forget that you can say no to things that don&amp;rsquo;t have any benefit to yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not in a selfish sense but it can be unbalanced if you&amp;rsquo;re just saying yes to a lot of things because you can, or because you have some knowledge to share, rather than because you want to participate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, you should go have a hard look at your projects and see which ones you don&amp;rsquo;t really want to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re better off with a short list of things you actually enjoy than a long list of crap that&amp;rsquo;ll just weigh on your mind.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You should publish your older works</title>
      <link>https://utf9k.net/blog/publish-old-works/</link>
      <description>I think it&#39;s a good idea to publish your existing work, even if you don&#39;t like it. You don&#39;t like it now but others earlier in their journey may appreciate it in a way that you can&#39;t anymore.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
      <author><name>Marcus Crane</name></author>
      <guid>https://utf9k.net/blog/publish-old-works/</guid>
      <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you haven&amp;rsquo;t seen it, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=X2wLP0izeJE&#34;&gt;Ira Glass on Storytelling 3&lt;/a&gt; is a video worth watching.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just the first few minutes is enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve recommended it a number of times in the last few years, and I&amp;rsquo;ll likely continue to do so for many years to come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To repeat the premise of the video, Ira describes taste as the gap between what you can accomplish right now, with your current skillset, and what you &lt;em&gt;know&lt;/em&gt; is good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your taste may be &amp;ldquo;killer&amp;rdquo;, as he puts it, but that gap means you recognise your work isn&amp;rsquo;t quite up to what you consider good enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That gap, and the craving to close it, can be motivating in the best of times, and straight up depressing in others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While progression over time will close your own gap, I would also point out the taste (and gap) of others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your taste will evolve over time, but others may be far ahead or behind your current progression of taste (if we pretend there is such a thing as scale of taste for a minute)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I&amp;rsquo;m trying to say is that, if you&amp;rsquo;re a painter for example, you might dislike your latest work. You may even think your work from 5 years ago is utter rubbish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps but don&amp;rsquo;t mistake that for thinking no one else is or can ever appreciate it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Someone years from now may strumble upon your back catalogue (online or off) and find a great deal of inspiration, knowledge or appreciation that you yourself don&amp;rsquo;t hold presently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like to think the same applies for software and &amp;ldquo;old&amp;rdquo; source code as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It gets a bit asterisky with things like objectively uncompilable code, custom frameworks that have security bugs and so on but you may have source code or old projects you think are bad, that others can gain inspiration from or just generally appreciate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arguably, that&amp;rsquo;s the only reason I leave anything I&amp;rsquo;ve written online is that maybe someone else might get some use out of it in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, while this can somewhat apply to software, I made a note to write this post a long time ago, in response to some artist friends who wondered why they would ever upload their old work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For someone who doesn&amp;rsquo;t make or generally seek out artworks, my own taste is pretty weak so I might appreciate an entry level &amp;ldquo;low taste&amp;rdquo; piece of work more than whatever is considered to be an &amp;ldquo;acquired taste&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s plenty of low tasters out there so you should try and embrace them :)&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
