<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>utf9k</title>
    <link>https://utf9k.net/tags/career/</link>
    <description>Posts from utf9k</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <author>
      <name>Marcus Crane</name>
      <email>marcus@utf9k.net</email>
    </author>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2022 16:40:00 +1300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://utf9k.net/tags/career/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>I didn&#39;t want to be an astronaut as a kid</title>
      <link>https://utf9k.net/blog/not-being-an-astronaut/</link>
      <description>Some thoughts on what career I thought I might like as a kid</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2022 16:40:00 +1300</pubDate>
      <author><name>Marcus Crane</name></author>
      <guid>https://utf9k.net/blog/not-being-an-astronaut/</guid>
      <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;For those who read my blog, you&amp;rsquo;ll know that one of the long running arcs is documenting my thoughts as I enter each new job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://utf9k.net/blog/day-xero&#34;&gt;Day Xero&lt;/a&gt; was initially just a standalone post I slapped together as I departed for my first day as a member of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.xero.com/nz/about/graduate/&#34;&gt;Xero graduate program&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. It was since joined by &lt;a href=&#34;https://utf9k.net/blog/day-one&#34;&gt;Day One&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mercedes-benz-trucks.com/content/mbo/markets/en_NZ/home.html&#34;&gt;Mercedes-Benz&lt;/a&gt;) and &lt;a href=&#34;https://utf9k.net/blog/day-two&#34;&gt;Day Two&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vendhq.com/nz/&#34;&gt;Vend&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;) and I&amp;rsquo;m sure in time there will inevitably be a few more entries but for now, I&amp;rsquo;m pretty happy where I am.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initially, I didn&amp;rsquo;t think too much about where I wanted to eventually end up nor did I ever actually expect to end up here in the first place. Back when I worked my shitty retail jobs, I was convinced that I had &amp;ldquo;missed the boat&amp;rdquo;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; so I never had any solid ambitions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That brings us to the title of this post. I remembered about a year or so back that when I was younger, I had this dumb idea that I wanted to be a &amp;ldquo;skateboarding CEO&amp;rdquo;. I&amp;rsquo;m sure I took it quite literally when I was younger but I think I what I actually found cool was the idea of constrast. It&amp;rsquo;s fun to break some expectations (and rules!) in a respectful way and as a kid, I was probably more interested in the idea of &amp;ldquo;being a unprofessional professional&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These days, I don&amp;rsquo;t focus so much on the CEO part&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; as I do on the contrast bit. For anyone who follows me on social media, you&amp;rsquo;ll have noticed my recent &amp;ldquo;obsession&amp;rdquo; with &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kumamon&#34;&gt;Kumamon&lt;/a&gt;, the loveable Japanese bear who represents the Kumatoto region.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, I do actually enjoy watching various bits of content by Kumamon after recently rediscovering him. I&amp;rsquo;ve actually found the fact that such ridiculous content can continue to exist, even in the midst of the confusing times we live in. Nothing gets rid of stress like popping open a video of a goofy bear falling over or whatever antics he&amp;rsquo;s up to this week but that&amp;rsquo;s besides the point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other purpose of my silly &amp;ldquo;obsession&amp;rdquo; is that it acts as a type of contrast I alluded to earlier. Growing up, I always believed that to be successful meant being super serious and dedicated to a fault. You always see hackers and so on coding away into the wee hours of the night in movie and such. Well, this is my little contribution towards dispelling the idea&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:5&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; that being or doing silly things is at odds with being capable. You can be both at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not just Kumamon mind you. There are other things like some of my favourite shirts and what not but they all basically represent the same idea in some form or another. I also just find it funny, in an absurd sense, seeing myself in a goofy shirt while I default to &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Resting_bitch_face&#34;&gt;RBF&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I can&amp;rsquo;t claim that it does or doesn&amp;rsquo;t have any effect, I also like to think that if anyone finds anything I do worth looking up to&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:6&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, that it&amp;rsquo;s somewhat comforting to know that you don&amp;rsquo;t have to be a super 10x hardcore asshole to accomplish things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now if I still took the &amp;ldquo;skateboarding CEO&amp;rdquo; idea literally, I would be (and was!) quite disappointed because it would be years and years until I accomplish it but by looking at it from a different angle, I realised that I already kinda made it there. At a smaller scale to be sure, but once you come to terms with the idea that bigger isn&amp;rsquo;t always better, it can be pretty comforting to have smaller, more achievable ambitions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, that&amp;rsquo;s probably enough of that for now. I&amp;rsquo;ve only really mentioned the above to one person I can think of but I figure it&amp;rsquo;d be handy to write it out so &lt;a href=&#34;https://utf9k.net/blog/zettelkasten-blog-a-good-idea/&#34;&gt;I can refer to it again in future&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps it&amp;rsquo;ll change over time and I&amp;rsquo;ll believe in the idea of being a 20xer instead but either way, being able to review your trajectory through writing is a pretty neat idea and while I can&amp;rsquo;t really enjoy it so much, I hope someone down the line can enjoy seeing my years of progress condensed into a handful of posts and possibly get some use out of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A bit of a misnomer on my part since I never went to university. Instead I went near insane from 3 years of retail before attending &lt;a href=&#34;https://devacademy.co.nz&#34;&gt;Enspiral Dev Academy&lt;/a&gt; as a last ditch effort before giving up. That was complimented by years of being a hobbyist prior and a couple more years of doing side projects and being rejected from jobs before I finally got my entrance into the industry.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Technically I work for &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lightspeedhq.com&#34;&gt;Lightspeed&lt;/a&gt; but I work on Vend. The product is referred to as Vend by Lightspeed but eventually we&amp;rsquo;ll just be part of Lightspeed. I don&amp;rsquo;t know for a fact that has been explicitly mentioned but it&amp;rsquo;s hardly a secret if you look at the trajectory on the public website.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was actually rejected from a university computer science course for not having enough math credits. Probably because I found Statistics boring and would skip class to go fiddle with HTML in the school library instead. Nowadays I have my rejection letter (aka &amp;ldquo;diploma&amp;rdquo;) framed on my desk at work.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Large companies, especially anything VC funded, are overrated. Keeping it manageable with little to no debt is where it&amp;rsquo;s at if you ask me. Being propped up by large amounts of outside funding and becoming &amp;ldquo;planet scale&amp;rdquo; is just asking for a slow death in my book. Even worse is the idea of just bailing out at the IPO stage and leaving all of your employees holding the bag with a company that gets put into maintenance mode.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:5&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which I myself held in the past to a solid extent!&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:6&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To date, I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten two emails of thanks which is two more than I ever expected to get from this website. I also expect that &lt;a href=&#34;https://utf9k.net/blog/publish-old-works/&#34;&gt;old posts may get dug up in future&lt;/a&gt; without my knowledge at all which I look forward to. If not, that&amp;rsquo;s perfectly fine because with my goldfish memory, I can enjoy my old posts. I once re-read &lt;a href=&#34;https://utf9k.net/blog/deepfakes&#34;&gt;deepfakes&lt;/a&gt; and thought &amp;ldquo;Damn, I never knew any of this.&amp;rdquo;. Of course, I did know it at some point but entirely forgot it all&amp;hellip;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day Two</title>
      <link>https://utf9k.net/blog/day-two/</link>
      <description>Thoughts as I enter the third job of my career in the software industry</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 12:01:00 +1300</pubDate>
      <author><name>Marcus Crane</name></author>
      <guid>https://utf9k.net/blog/day-two/</guid>
      <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve recently started as a Senior Site Reliability Engineer at &lt;a href=&#34;https://lightspeedhq.com/&#34;&gt;Lightspeed&lt;/a&gt; which means that it&amp;rsquo;s time for the sequel to &lt;a href=&#34;https://utf9k.net/blog/day-one&#34;&gt;Day One&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the uninitiated, I write a new post summing up the excitement and concerns I have whenever I start a new job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not actually sure if I&amp;rsquo;ve ever explicitly noted that this is intended to be an ongoing series but yeah, ideally I write a new entry every time I start a new job going forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea is that I can look back and laugh at how much I did or didn&amp;rsquo;t know. I realise that from the shoes of a beginner, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to assume that long timers are magically gifted or Just Knew It All so in the event I make it somewhere interesting, this generally serves as proof that I had my doubts along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m actually quite overdue with this entry since I&amp;rsquo;m a little over a week into my new job already. I&amp;rsquo;ll probably keep it kind of brief as well since I keep staying up late&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; but I did make a couple of quick notes that I&amp;rsquo;ll try to address.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, let&amp;rsquo;s get started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;interviewing&#34;&gt;Interviewing&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I actually don&amp;rsquo;t mind interviewing so much these days but I do dread the idea of getting some overly technical, google-esque interview. I never took computer science&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref1:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; so if you ask me about B-tree&amp;rsquo;s or whatever then I&amp;rsquo;m out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a matter of fact, an interview prior to the ones with Lightspeed had me trying to write a sudoku solver. I gave it a crack but I didn&amp;rsquo;t have much to show so 10 minutes before I end, I just ended it early to save myself the humiliation. That said, I pretty confidently said that I don&amp;rsquo;t enjoy this stuff, I&amp;rsquo;m comfortable saying as much and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t reflect what I do day to day anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, I got to show a bit of everything across the stack in the Lightspeed interview with even a bit of frontend polish just for kicks :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It definitely wasn&amp;rsquo;t required but I opted to spend a bit of time on it. It&amp;rsquo;s good practice for sprucing up my website anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-first-day&#34;&gt;My first day&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;These posts don&amp;rsquo;t generally show when I&amp;rsquo;ve started but it&amp;rsquo;s probably a bit more appropriate (and relevant) of a timespan as my career progresses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had a poke around a bunch of Slack channels and was in two minds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly: wow, there&amp;rsquo;s some really cool best practice stuff going on. Secondly: Ahh geez, everyone is definitely going to be smarter than me and doing well crafted stuff while I&amp;rsquo;m super rusty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thankfully everyone is really nice and the onboarding has been pretty comprehensive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;slos&#34;&gt;SLOs&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Funnily enough, I saw a bunch of SLO monitors and my eyes probably dilated a bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.xero.com/nz/&#34;&gt;Xero&lt;/a&gt;, my team helped push the introduction of SLOs and I was in the SLO space for the better part of a year and a half and I still feel like I&amp;rsquo;ve forgotten all of it in some capacity, haha.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s really stupid like I&amp;rsquo;ve run 3 part workshops on SLOs + alerting, helped teams instrument their products and my brain is still like &amp;ldquo;I&amp;quot;m very unqualified in this space&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m sure this happens with most every domain anyway. Once I get back into it and brush up on source material again, I&amp;rsquo;m sure I&amp;rsquo;ll remember all the niche details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still such at math, and by extension statistics and what not though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Realistically, I&amp;rsquo;m probably just scared that people will ask me questions on the spot I won&amp;rsquo;t have the answers to, as if that&amp;rsquo;s how it would go down. I also have an entire team I&amp;rsquo;m part of so that&amp;rsquo;s a dumb story to tell yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;work-life-balance&#34;&gt;Work life balance&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This time around, I&amp;rsquo;m definitely focusing on clocking in and out near enough on time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s not to say I dislike my job, quite the opposite in fact. Thinking that the more hours you do magically correlates to more productivity is a lie. Productivity in general is a lie anyway. I have enough green cubes on Github without even trying, thank you very much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My thoughts on this currently would just be a regurgitation of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.oliverburkeman.com/books&#34;&gt;Four Thousand Weeks&lt;/a&gt; by Oliver Burkeman.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It looks like a self help book but it&amp;rsquo;s not. Just a reminder that always striving towards things, for the sake of &amp;ldquo;productivity&amp;rdquo;, is not a good idea generally. It&amp;rsquo;s worth a read!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;job-titles&#34;&gt;Job titles&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;It took me about a good week or so to put the &amp;ldquo;Senior&amp;rdquo; prefix in my bio and even then, I self-deprecatingly tacked &amp;ldquo;(allegedly)&amp;rdquo; on the end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think of myself as a Junior Senior, in that I just acquired this title but I guess it was bestowed upon me by passing a test so I guess I earned it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I dunno, I feel the same and I often forget that I&amp;rsquo;ve quote unquote made it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I try not to think about it and remember that there&amp;rsquo;s a whole team I&amp;rsquo;m part of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-team&#34;&gt;The team&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;They&amp;rsquo;re all really nice people that I can&amp;rsquo;t fault or have any reservations about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to consciously be a little bit more myself by bringing the sillier aspects to work such as my &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kumamon&#34;&gt;Kumamon&lt;/a&gt; obsession.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an example, I really enjoy Kumamon but even more, I find the contrast of &amp;ldquo;an industry professional&amp;rdquo; being a big fan of a cute Japanese bear even funnier. I imagine it&amp;rsquo;s weirdly jarring but I also like that it forcefully breaks any illusion of being unapproachable or overly serious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, my less serious aspects like shitposting people (although never punching down or sideways) via DMs have ended up being helpful for bridging teams who don&amp;rsquo;t communicate so easily. You can get to know individuals and figure out how to build ties with common elements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone can equally laugh at my Kumamon obsession while knowing that I&amp;rsquo;m in on the joke for example. Maybe it helps ultimately build a squillion dollar product that ultimately would have fallen apart if things were too serious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I dunno, I just want to build useful software and learn things anyway. Getting too invested into any single business, that may ultimately collapse at the whim of a newly-installed post-IPO board, is a bit of a mistake waiting to happen so just enjoy it while it lasts :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;now-what&#34;&gt;Now what&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m still onboarding and perhaps I&amp;rsquo;ll have more to write about career stuff. I think I&amp;rsquo;ll be pretty happy here for a while and I&amp;rsquo;ve got quite a bit to learn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With lockdown again here in New Zealand and my &lt;a href=&#34;https://utf9k.net/blog/ride-the-curve/&#34;&gt;brief health issues earlier this year&lt;/a&gt;, I had purposely decided not to think about work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, I was invited by the recruiter to interview so I never really plan to work here, it all came as quite a surprise!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The more technical posts I&amp;rsquo;ve written, such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://utf9k.net/blog/conditional-gitconfig/&#34;&gt;Conditionally setting your gitconfig&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://utf9k.net/blog/wsl2-vhd-issue/&#34;&gt;Fixing a WSL2 VHD conversion issue&lt;/a&gt;, continue to gain quite a bit of traffic which is interesting since I don&amp;rsquo;t do very much promotion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have some vague intention to dig through manpages and what not to see what other niche things I can dig up. I don&amp;rsquo;t intend to turn this site into some sort of &amp;ldquo;Top 5 Git Commands&amp;rdquo; hellhole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given that a few people reached out to me as a result, I&amp;rsquo;m aware that more than a few seem to have gotten real value out of problems that I was just solving for myself ultimately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://utf9k.net/questions&#34;&gt;questions&lt;/a&gt; section is still the place to go for brief, niche snippets but I would like to do some deep dives in future if anything useful comes out of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whatever, I&amp;rsquo;m just rambling at this point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until next time, see ya.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unrelated to work, just doomscrolling Twitter too much.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref1:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ride the curve</title>
      <link>https://utf9k.net/blog/ride-the-curve/</link>
      <description>A post from a darker time on how to better think about taking a break</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 May 2021 10:40:00 +1300</pubDate>
      <author><name>Marcus Crane</name></author>
      <guid>https://utf9k.net/blog/ride-the-curve/</guid>
      <content type="html">&lt;div class=&#34;notice&#34;&gt;
  &lt;hr class=&#34;hidden&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;h3&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;🚣‍♀️&lt;/span&gt;It&amp;#39;s rough seas out there!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not so long ago, I was struggling with instances of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Depersonalization&#34;&gt;something very unfamiliar&lt;/a&gt; , which scared the shit out of me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As one of many distractions, I popped open a text editor and started writing about my life so far and this is what came out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve strongly resisted the urge to make any edits, beyond adding links for context. All footnotes were already written inline with the draft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t fully reread it nor do I really intend to. I also never got to the actual point of the title, which is what I started off with as a prompt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short, I&amp;rsquo;m trying to relax more and look after myself. That doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean stopping work but riding the momentum I already built up, whether I realise it or not.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;hr class=&#34;hidden&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generally, I tend to worry a lot about what things might look like in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If it all turns to custard, will I have transferrable skills that are sought after?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My tendency is to frame the tech industry as a sort of gold rush that sooner or later will dry up. I imagine that maybe it will hit market saturation or be dismissed due to intense distrust thanks to key/buzzwords like Surveillance and Algorithms that always seem poised to spiral out of control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;del&gt;some&lt;/del&gt; most ways, this is a ridiculous thing to worry about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly because an industry that can service other industries (see: accounting, consulting, compliance etc) rarely run out of business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secondly, most things are cyclical so a crash here will peak once again over there. We only have to look at various bubbles and crashes (see: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dot-com_bubble&#34;&gt;the dotcom boom&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Financial_crisis_of_2007%E2%80%932008&#34;&gt;Global Financial Crisis&lt;/a&gt; or even the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/COVID-19_recession&#34;&gt;Coronavirus Pandemic&lt;/a&gt; which is still ongoing)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, the final and true answer is that no one can know the future. We can predict things, often with some accuracy but us humans are unpredictable so even sane assumptions can fall apart in an instant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;abandoning-ship&#34;&gt;Abandoning ship&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I was towards the end of my teenage years (I&amp;rsquo;m only 26!), I figured I had missed the boat when it came to &amp;ldquo;Computer Science&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I liked messing around with web pages and I thought the internet was fascinating despite only having a vague understanding of how it worked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember trawling through forum posts for MMOs and absolutely loving the technical explanations of why Final Fantasy 14 developers &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/ffxiv/comments/6h4129/yoshida_acknowledging_glamour_importance/divdh85/&#34;&gt;struggled to allocate more bag slots&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://forum.square-enix.com/ffxiv/threads/125277-Triple-Monitor-Display?p=1631847&amp;amp;highlight=Minagawa#post1631847&#34;&gt;the troubles with aspects&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite all this, and years of trawling &lt;a href=&#34;https://news.ycombinator.com&#34;&gt;Hacker News&lt;/a&gt; daily which built up a fairly solid vocabulary, I never actually properly started programming until what I thought was quite late.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I considered myself a hobbyist and had dabbled in a bit of Python but I didn&amp;rsquo;t &amp;ldquo;get&amp;rdquo; any of it for a long time, probably since I didn&amp;rsquo;t have a mental model to hang any of it in a useful way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I distinctly remember &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bbc.com/news/technology-34066941&#34;&gt;some BBC article came out ranking the likelihood of job automation&lt;/a&gt; had came out in my third year of retail. It listed retail workers as having something like a 97% chance of being automated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nowadays, I think back on that and find it kind of funny. Due in part to being a technical hobbyist, I would daydream about automating parts of my job and thinking about how inefficient the systems seemed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Probably for that reason, I thought I could &amp;ldquo;feel&amp;rdquo; it coming, like a rising tide that would swallow me up and that fear was a useful, although probably not healthy motivator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Between that fear and a general sense of worthlessness and disappointment, I decided to throw my eggs in one basket and attend a web development bootcamp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m sure for some, it was just a brief chance to dabble in a profession to see if they&amp;rsquo;re interested but for me, at that time, I felt it was my last chance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saddled with the idea of spending the next 50+ years, pushing shopping carts and being derailed into conversations that amounted to &amp;ldquo;What if the store just simply made everything more efficient&amp;rdquo; for the 600th time, I honestly did not expect to live this long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, as for how I came up with the funding: Doing a lot of saving coupled with a bank loan for a &amp;ldquo;cruise to Japan&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;actually-finding-a-job&#34;&gt;Actually finding a job&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Going to &lt;a href=&#34;https://devacademy.co.nz/&#34;&gt;a bootcamp&lt;/a&gt; was a step in the right direction and a chance to understand the industry but I will never claim you can attend one and instantly become a fully fledged developer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plenty of people were lucky and found side jobs or internships relatively quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was arguably unlucky in that I persisted for an extra year on minimal savings and spent what felt like the majority of every day pouring over crap, building side projects and doing tutorials, filling out job applications and probably trying to not cry a lot of the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a side note, a man in his 40s or so moved into our flat at one point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first, he seemed fine but progressively shared some conspiratorial views until I found out he was literally a white supremacist. I&amp;rsquo;m not misusing the term literally here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of his friends once talked about beating me to death while I was in my room, with the lights of, pretending to be out of the house.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This inspired me to learn how to set up a &lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.com/&#34;&gt;Discord&lt;/a&gt; bot that would poll our router for connected devices and I could query to see if I felt safe to come home. Odds are, if he was home, he was in the lounge and would say Hello and draw me into a two hour, mostly one sided conversation where I would nod and say &amp;ldquo;H-hah, sure, I guess the UN could be trying to control the population&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In hindsight, I was probably pretty stressed during that time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;working-to-keep-working&#34;&gt;Working to keep working&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;With going into too much detail, I had the good fortune to work at one of New Zealand&amp;rsquo;s largest tech companies and at present, I work for one of the largest car companies. Ironic, given I don&amp;rsquo;t drive.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite all that, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if I relax enough. Actually, I&amp;rsquo;m not even sure if I know what that is exactly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, I&amp;rsquo;m not a robot and unfortunately I&amp;rsquo;m not a machine either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like playing videogames but I&amp;rsquo;d dropped off a lot since I started working. Last year, I even got annoyed that I didn&amp;rsquo;t game very much so I sold my gaming desktop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I figured I&amp;rsquo;d double down on research and what not and try to do more productive things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is probably near enough the root of my troubles and why I&amp;rsquo;m writing it all down today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think I still have that driving fear that I&amp;rsquo;ll be made redundant one day. I probably will and that&amp;rsquo;s perfectly fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s nowhere near strong enough as it was back then when it felt like a choice between life and death but it&amp;rsquo;s still enough to make me hesitate between reading a book and playing a game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps I overcorrected a lot. I like the idea that a to do list is better framed as a &amp;ldquo;things i could do&amp;rdquo; list since that sums it up nicely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s easy to imagine side projects and then see them tower up. More and more until you realise you could never achieve these in your lifetime. The mere thought of them becomes exhausting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thankfully my blog isn&amp;rsquo;t quite like that. I have a couple of small goals buried somewhere but I don&amp;rsquo;t feel bad about not posting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the most part, I just imagine no one reads this anyway. I heard once from a reader which was really cool and sometimes I peek at analytics to see a lot of people seem to get value from &lt;a href=&#34;https://utf9k.net/blog/wsl2-vhd-issue/&#34;&gt;my Windows 10 VHD post&lt;/a&gt;. Beyond those technical things, I struggle to imagine anyone investing time into these.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;whats-next&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s next?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I had been meaning to write a post about my intentions with my blog. I&amp;rsquo;m still active and I have things on my list but mostly it feels like something driven by guilt and fear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A portfolio to say that I existed but not one with enough value to actually act as a portfolio!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My intention going forward is to encourage myself to post a bit more often but with less lengthy content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Things that I find interesting and are worth sharing as well as a few larger, &amp;ldquo;original&amp;rdquo; posts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve got one that I&amp;rsquo;m particularly excited to get struck into that&amp;rsquo;s a little quirky and is a bit of a fun investigation story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I run into technical troubles from time to time and I&amp;rsquo;ll generally still share those but they don&amp;rsquo;t really come up often and admittedly, I don&amp;rsquo;t find them hugely interesting unless some sort of a story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve also changed the structure of the site a little bit. You can see any drafts at &lt;a href=&#34;https://next.utf9k.net&#34;&gt;next.utf9k.net&lt;/a&gt; and I manually merge things into the live branch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given that there&amp;rsquo;s a concept of &amp;ldquo;staging&amp;rdquo; where I can add things piecemeal, I might start managing longer posts as Github issues where I can make notes to myself and sort of &amp;ldquo;work out in the open&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean a story in the open is guaranteed to happen but adds a little bit more structure that might help with stories that are otherwise a bit overwhelming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My tendency is to write them all in one sitting (like this post) with an optional review but it&amp;rsquo;s probably a bit healthier to piece things out and not potentially feel so overwhelmed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;beyond-the-site&#34;&gt;Beyond the site&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Of course, this was just an excuse to shoe horn in some thoughts about this site into an otherwise fairly personal post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t feel that I&amp;rsquo;ve ever really shied away from talking about my feelings very much so I don&amp;rsquo;t consider sharing this to be a huge effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having said that, maybe there&amp;rsquo;s some value for other people in reading these sorts of things?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m sure others can relate when I say I feel a bit paradoxical about a lot of things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, the idea of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fear_of_missing_out&#34;&gt;FOMO&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/01/26/business/against-hustle-culture-rise-and-grind-tgim.html&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Hustle culture&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; is stupid and unhealthy, yet at the same time I&amp;rsquo;ve clearly just described what is basically someone who struggles to ignore it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t feel like I have to do anything but at the same time, I get a bit itchy when I&amp;rsquo;m away from something constructive for too long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think I would actually hate the idea of being retired on a beach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would like to be retired with &lt;a href=&#34;https://howlongtobeat.com/user/Sentry&#34;&gt;my videogame backlog&lt;/a&gt; however.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve got some personal (and mental) struggles to deal with and perhaps I&amp;rsquo;ll share some of those.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I gotta head off now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until next time, happy travels!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MMO developers seem to have a tendency to be more open than most, probably because subscriptions from the fans directly keep them going rather than publisher deals.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have my restricted license but my flat is quite literally on a main road so we don&amp;rsquo;t have any place to park.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
