<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>utf9k</title>
    <link>https://utf9k.net/tags/tips/</link>
    <description>Posts from utf9k</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <author>
      <name>Marcus Crane</name>
      <email>marcus@utf9k.net</email>
    </author>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 15:24:00 +1300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://utf9k.net/tags/tips/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Miserable presentation tips</title>
      <link>https://utf9k.net/blog/miserable-presentation-tips/</link>
      <description>It works well for me but I don&#39;t recommend it!</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 15:24:00 +1300</pubDate>
      <author><name>Marcus Crane</name></author>
      <guid>https://utf9k.net/blog/miserable-presentation-tips/</guid>
      <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;When the thought of having to give a presentation comes up, my usual reaction is that it might be fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve given a decent handful of talks over the last few years to medium-ish audiences, with the largest being to around 100 people. For various reasons, the most recent ones have been via video calls but I&amp;rsquo;ve done a couple in person and they don&amp;rsquo;t feel that different in hindsight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is where I could start to hock my self help book&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and say &amp;ldquo;Imagine the audience in their underwear&amp;rdquo; but instead, why not dump out my brain on paper so that you too, for the low low price of $0, can also think about presentations upside down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My general threshold for being &amp;ldquo;comfortable&amp;rdquo; with giving a talk is about 10 or more people, where I&amp;rsquo;m kinda awful when it comes to groups greater than 1 person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for why that is, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to imagine in a group of a few people, you stand out a lot more if you aren&amp;rsquo;t say much (or are saying a lot!) with the best way to &amp;ldquo;hide&amp;rdquo; being to act normal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why wouldn&amp;rsquo;t the same apply for a group where you&amp;rsquo;re centre stage? It does I&amp;rsquo;m sure but it&amp;rsquo;s easy to imagine the group as a whole not paying attention to what you&amp;rsquo;re saying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a safe bet that it&amp;rsquo;s a reflection of my time in school, doing English class speeches where students, myself included, would zone out while someone had to give their presentation, even if it didn&amp;rsquo;t feel like it to the presenter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, I should be overly clear here and say that this line of thought should not be taken seriously! It can be a useful tool but if you start to genuinely believe no one cares, that becomes dangerous the further you go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reality is that no one would turn up if they weren&amp;rsquo;t interested, or wanting to support your output and you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t doubt it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my mind, I put it in the same category as receiving complements where my initial reaction is to downplay them, partly out of embarrassment from receiving attention and partly because it doesn&amp;rsquo;t happen regularly meaning it&amp;rsquo;s not normalised for me. Feeling that way doesn&amp;rsquo;t make it any less accurate or make you any less deserving of it however!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back to our fantasy worldview where we falsely believe no one is paying attention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this in mind, I always try to make sure the talk I&amp;rsquo;m giving is something I would find interesting myself. In this view of things, I&amp;rsquo;m the only one hearing myself talk which means I want to make sure I don&amp;rsquo;t get bored of what I have to say.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Put another way, I try to give a talk that my past self would enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Going a step further, you might even imagine that the talk itself is besides the point. It&amp;rsquo;s an artefact that you&amp;rsquo;ll be discarding, with the fun part being the research process. It&amp;rsquo;s like free motivation to look into something that you otherwise wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have found interesting.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main underlying idea is to expect nothing with any response being a positive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you get a positive response, then great!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you get a neutral response, you didn&amp;rsquo;t lose (or gain) anything and likely learned a bunch on top of +5 Presentation EXP&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting a negative response is unlikely given the vast majority of people don&amp;rsquo;t like confrontation. In the rare event it does happen, it sounds like you made something that compelled someone to have an opinion which is a strange win if you think about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This should all be taken with a large pinch of salt (and therapy?) but used in the right way, it can be a handy story to tell yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Merely saying &amp;quot;	Don&amp;rsquo;t worry about it&amp;quot; is easy but getting to a place where you can believe it, even for a short while is the hardest part of all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t read enough self-help books yet to have the motivation to write a self-help book 😛&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m assuming here that you&amp;rsquo;ve volunteered to give a presentation instead of a boring business thing.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
