<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>utf9k</title>
    <link>https://utf9k.net/tags/people/</link>
    <description>Posts from utf9k</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <author>
      <name>Marcus Crane</name>
      <email>marcus@utf9k.net</email>
    </author>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2022 22:00:00 +1300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://utf9k.net/tags/people/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>So you have (or are) competition</title>
      <link>https://utf9k.net/blog/so-you-have-or-are-competition/</link>
      <description>A series of questions that I would ask my past self in certain awkward situations</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2022 22:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
      <author><name>Marcus Crane</name></author>
      <guid>https://utf9k.net/blog/so-you-have-or-are-competition/</guid>
      <content type="html">&lt;div class=&#34;notice&#34;&gt;
  &lt;hr class=&#34;hidden&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;h3&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;🧪&lt;/span&gt;This post is a sort of weird living document of sorts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be honest, I got kind of lazy towards the end so I&amp;rsquo;m pushing out what I wrote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That said, I also intend to add to the list of bullet points as time goes on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s the sort of post that is harder to capture the further away you are from the situation in question!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;hr class=&#34;hidden&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generally on this site I have two types of posts: Relatively straight forward technical posts and long-winded, more experimental posts that I would just link to myself in the past if time travel existed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post is heavily one of the latter and it revolved around a certain type of unintentional competition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Specifically, it&amp;rsquo;s targeted at an awkward gap at which I, and I&amp;rsquo;m sure many of us, have fallen into from time to time which I&amp;rsquo;ll define in a moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In particular, these are scenarios I&amp;rsquo;ve encountered in a work setting but I suppose they could apply just as equally in any sort of community from friend groups to event committees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t know but I&amp;rsquo;ll try to keep this whole thing general enough so as to leave it open for your own intepretation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll probably also make this a &amp;ldquo;living document&amp;rdquo; that I add things to as I think of them. It&amp;rsquo;ll be pretty messy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-twin-scenarios&#34;&gt;The twin scenarios&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;a) You have just created and launched something into the wild, only to find that someone else in your area is already invested in that problem domain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b) Someone else has just created and launched something into the wild, which you have just discovered and you aren&amp;rsquo;t sure how to feel about it&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These two scenarios are the same scenario, just from different angles. Personally, I&amp;rsquo;ve both caused Scenario A and felt the effects of Scenario B. I&amp;rsquo;ve even experienced both A and B for the same problem domain within the same year, which felt a bit like karma funnily enough!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These scenarios happen all the time for everything I&amp;rsquo;m sure and neither side can feel pleasant. Emotions get heated, people get protective of &amp;ldquo;their&amp;rdquo; domains that they&amp;rsquo;ve invested time into and things can turn a bit sour if they&amp;rsquo;re not evaluated properly with some perspective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As with all things emotional, you should step back and think about the bigger picture!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re in that narrow period of time, or just want some tips for next time on how you might deal with it then here are some thoughts you might want to mull over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m just going to throw out bullet points because&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a) It&amp;rsquo;s quicker and I&amp;rsquo;m being lazy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;but also&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b) I can&amp;rsquo;t give you the answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s never an open and shut case, as much as you might want to cite time investment, experience, job titles and all sorts of other things you can reach for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes the best answer is the one that sucks and it hasn&amp;rsquo;t arrived at a good time but there&amp;rsquo;s never really a good time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh and one last thing: When you invest time and effort into something, it&amp;rsquo;s natural to feel emotional! You can&amp;rsquo;t unlogic yourself out of those feelings and you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t try to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re not up for the task, don&amp;rsquo;t read these points and beat yourself up by any means. That&amp;rsquo;s not what this is for!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are just things to ask yourself in a neutral light. Don&amp;rsquo;t judge yourself for actions that have already passed. It&amp;rsquo;s more about deciding what to do next and what you might do differently next time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;im-experiencing-scenario-a&#34;&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m experiencing Scenario A&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;So you&amp;rsquo;ve just created something and you&amp;rsquo;ve been informed that your idea already exists in some other form.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How was the reaction that you received?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Was it welcoming to a newcomer into that space?
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If yes, great!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If no, that&amp;rsquo;s not very nice
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why is that? Does this happen a lot?
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If yes, that sounds like a them problem right? Something keeps going wrong that people arrive at the conclusion that they need to start from scratch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;im-experiencing-b&#34;&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m experiencing B&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;So you&amp;rsquo;ve have or are actively creating something and you&amp;rsquo;ve been informed that someone has just stepped into your problem domain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How are you feeling about this news right now?
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are you excited for some new competition, regardless of whether you agree with the approach?
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If yes, great, that sounds healthy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If no, why is that?
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do you feel that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t compare in terms of quality to your work?
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If yes, why does that matter?
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does a new offering existing somehow take away from your work?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is your work able to stand on its own merits?
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If no, should it exist if it can&amp;rsquo;t support itself and needs ie; political cover to stay alive?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do you feel that people don&amp;rsquo;t appreciate it fully?
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do you have solid documentation and announcements that people can discover on their own time?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If your approach communicated clearly?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is the problem space too deep in the weeds for people who are not domain experts to &amp;ldquo;get it&amp;rdquo;?
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can you considered making use of metaphors, or just general storytelling to help bridge the communication gap&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Has enough time actually passed for people to &amp;ldquo;have time&amp;rdquo; to learn about your offering and to &amp;ldquo;get it&amp;rdquo;?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have you actually talked to anyone about your problem area?
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do you know that this problem area is actually a problem?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do other people see this problem area as being a problem?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do other people have this problem enough to &amp;ldquo;feel&amp;rdquo; that it is a problem?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is the length of the problem only felt in short enough bursts that others are not motivated enough to seek out a solution?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Did you feel an emotion reaction to this news?
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If yes, why is that?
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do you consider yourself to be an expert in this particular domain?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do you spend a lot of time working in this particular domain?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is this particular domain just one that you spend time in or your core one?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you felt an overwhelming emotion reaction, is your identity and sense of self worth tied into this domain?
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Should it be? Maybe it is more than you realise?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do you feel that you could walk away from this problem domain and not feel a great loss?
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do you need to diversity your identity a bit more and find some different hobbies?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We are all that person who reads a book while walking</title>
      <link>https://utf9k.net/blog/walking-while-reading/</link>
      <description>Honestly, this post is weird and dumb. I wouldn&#39;t recommend it.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 13:02:46 +1300</pubDate>
      <author><name>Marcus Crane</name></author>
      <guid>https://utf9k.net/blog/walking-while-reading/</guid>
      <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;There is a person who lives in my general area that I&amp;rsquo;ve spotted two or three times in the almost three years that I have lived at my flat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He has a book open and reads it, while walking and for the most part, seemingly not paying any attention to where he is going.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It feels entirely ridiculous and comical so it&amp;rsquo;s definitely noticeable whenever I do spot him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That behaviour is something I think I&amp;rsquo;ve seen before at school where you would have that one kid seemingly glued to a book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How that knowledge is used is beyond me since they never seem to do much else besides reading but that&amp;rsquo;s besides the point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As ridiculous as their actions seem, we&amp;rsquo;re effectively all that person now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anytime we get the urge to see what new chat message has arrived or whip out a device to flick through a music playlist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s really just the same behaviour but without the persistence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I probably never learned anything from quickly skimming my &amp;ldquo;Liked Songs&amp;rdquo; on Spotify while waiting for a traffic light though.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Address book sorting</title>
      <link>https://utf9k.net/blog/address-book-sorting/</link>
      <description>The macOS and iOS address book leaves a bit to be desired</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 22:48:00 +1300</pubDate>
      <author><name>Marcus Crane</name></author>
      <guid>https://utf9k.net/blog/address-book-sorting/</guid>
      <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;When I boot up an Apple device for the first time, it always strikes me as annoying to find that the address book is sorted by last name first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thinking about this further, I think the frustration stems from my being more unfamiliar with last names than first. It&amp;rsquo;s not like I don&amp;rsquo;t know their last names either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It could be a lookup issue in the sense that I have to visualise the full name of a person and then break off the end chunk and put it first. That is, in a sense that&amp;rsquo;s what my brain is doing rather than jumping straight to their first name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do wonder if last names are less commonly used? For example, I can&amp;rsquo;t remember the last time I ever referred to someone by their last name ie Ms. Blah.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would partly chalk that up to a mix of my age, tendency to hate overly formal things and my general professional which is&amp;hellip; not traditionally professional shall we say.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For that reason, I tend to think of people by their first names and I always dig out that setting and turn it off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It could be that it&amp;rsquo;s more the realm of business people, who have more formal connections (and business cards) than I do. For that reason, it might be that they don&amp;rsquo;t tend to use first names as prominently?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could google search it, and I will, but before then it makes me wonder how many other default settings are considered weird to other people?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Autocorrection is another one where I find that I need to toggle off all the assistance features or I&amp;rsquo;ll be driven mad. I prefer my screen real estate!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps there&amp;rsquo;s a committee of address book creators too, who uphold the guidelines of what makes a good address book. I&amp;rsquo;m just speculating at this point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d be interested to know what other default settings bug you! You can let me know through the variety of different mediums in the footer below.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Latency as a forcing function</title>
      <link>https://utf9k.net/blog/latency-as-a-forcing-function/</link>
      <description>Sometimes latency is good?</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2021 14:53:00 +1300</pubDate>
      <author><name>Marcus Crane</name></author>
      <guid>https://utf9k.net/blog/latency-as-a-forcing-function/</guid>
      <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m probably not alone in admitting that sometimes &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; checking work apps can be pretty hard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At my previous job, we used Slack and partly due to the cozy nature of some threads, I&amp;rsquo;d often find myself opening it without noticing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve witnessed colleagues do this too, often at social events, where they suddenly snap back to reality and realise &amp;ldquo;Wait, what the hell am I doing?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not that Slack isn&amp;rsquo;t the super snappiest application but compared to one of the current chat mediums at my workplace, it may as well be a bullet train in terms of latency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll give you a glimpse into what you could be enjoying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-perils-of-javascript&#34;&gt;The perils of Javascript&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;While Mattermost is primarily a web based chat application, I tend to use the desktop client which isn&amp;rsquo;t much more than an electron wrapper around the very same website so the experience is mostly the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The server is hosted on premises, for data sovereignty reasons, which means that all of the data is loaded direct from Germany with no CDNs in the middle for the very same reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That in itself I don&amp;rsquo;t have any trouble with but gosh, can it be slow!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s what I usually end up staring at a number of times&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;empty-frame.png&#34; alt=&#34;A screenshot of a dead Mattermost client. It&amp;amp;rsquo;s an electron desktop app but all it is rendering is a single tab and the rest of the screen is blank. There are no loading indicators at all.&#34;  /&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a user, I would hope for at least a loading spinner but that spinner is contained in the Javascript bundle which&amp;hellip; the server is sometimes too flaky to serve it seems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, when this happens, I usually reach for the View menu and click the following&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;clear-cache.png&#34; alt=&#34;A screenshot of the View menu for Mattermost. It shows a number of options with &amp;amp;ldquo;Clear cache and Reload&amp;amp;rdquo; being highlighted. This menu also contained an item called &amp;amp;ldquo;Developer Tools for Current Server&amp;amp;rdquo; which we will be accessing later.&#34;  /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The previously mentioned flakiness still causes troubles from time to time so it takes a couple of tries. I often click the &amp;ldquo;Developer Tools for Current Server&amp;rdquo; option seen above to see what exactly is happening under the hood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s what a dead request usually gives me, and is generally the cause of the blank frame you saw earlier&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;loading-stuck.png&#34; alt=&#34;A screenshot of the previously mentioned developer tools. They look identical to the usual browser developer tools. The Network tab is selected which shows a single HTTP request for a document that returned the status code 200 OK. It took 300 milliseconds but despite that, the frame is still blank. The browser tools give the impression that the application has finished loading despite that not being the case.&#34;  /&gt;&lt;p&gt;After a few retries, we&amp;rsquo;re able to fully load the application but only after an entire minute has passed!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;total-load-time.png&#34; alt=&#34;A screenshot of the Network tab which contains 87 requests. That&amp;amp;rsquo;s a lot! The network transfer waterfall spans 65 seconds which is crazy for a website. A number of the requests span anywhere between 300ms and 5 seconds.&#34;  /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Arguably, it gets even worse once we dig into some of the culprits. Here is one which is a Mattermost plugin called &lt;a href=&#34;https://integrations.mattermost.com/standup-raven/&#34;&gt;Standup Raven&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;standup-raven.png&#34; alt=&#34;A screenshot of the Network tab that has been cropped to just a couple of network transfers. One for a plugin called Standup Raven has been selected which took a total of 19 seconds to download!&#34;  /&gt;&lt;p&gt;A whopping 1/3 of the download time appears to be used up for a single plugin! To make matters worse, these plugins appear to be parsed first before any of the actual chat content is fetched so the Mattermost window sits unusable until all plugins are downloaded before progressing to fetch messages and channels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the network request, the bundle is &lt;em&gt;a whopping 1.8MB&lt;/em&gt; and that&amp;rsquo;s after being gzipped. That&amp;rsquo;s bigger than the actual client bundle itself!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My browser reported that the plugin was 7MB uncompressed so I was concerned that I was horribly misinterpreting this information, I looked up the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/standup-raven/standup-raven&#34;&gt;Github repository&lt;/a&gt; for Standup Raven and took a look at the latest release which is &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/standup-raven/standup-raven/releases/tag/v3.2.0&#34;&gt;v3.2.0&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sure enough, the plugin on offer was distributed as part of an 11.1MB &lt;code&gt;tar.gz&lt;/code&gt; archive and the bundle itself weighs in at &lt;code&gt;7.4MB&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;plugin-installation-size.png&#34; alt=&#34;A screenshot showing the Javascript bundle for Standup Raven open in the authors Downloads directory using macOS finder. This finder window is sitting open over the top of the latest Github release. The Github release shown distributes tar.gz bundles for Windows, macOS and Linux. Each tar.gz is 11MB with the downloaded bundle while the main.js bundle the author downloaded is 7.4MB. This lines up with the download size mentioned before.&#34;  /&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;whats-the-forcing-function-here&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s the forcing function here?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Given how flaky the Mattermost client can often be, I actually stopped using it for the most part.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I checked it maybe one or twice a day but for the most part, I don&amp;rsquo;t want anything to do with it and honestly, this has been great for my work life balance!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, not to say that I have any work life balance but at no point do I &amp;ldquo;fear&amp;rdquo; missing out because&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a) The experience is unmanagable to the point where I don&amp;rsquo;t want to be involved&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b) My other non-European colleagues tend to have the same troubles&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now these points might seem negative but funnily enough, it has actually delivered some pretty solid value as a quirk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given how much latency is sometimes involved, with messages taking a couple of seconds to send at times, the amount of user traffic at any given time is often quite low.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There isn&amp;rsquo;t a constant stream of discussions and emojis flooding into my laptop over websockets. It&amp;rsquo;s pure quiet bliss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A large part of that is due to timezones mind you but that only adds to the asychronous nature of Mattermost within our team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It feels more akin to a notice board or an old school forum where you can back and check your thread the next day, and despite what you might think, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t really have any effect on efficiency that I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If anything, I spend much less time checking Mattermost than I used to pouring over Slack due to FoMo or whatever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If it&amp;rsquo;s urgent, you can always page me!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;could-you-fix-this&#34;&gt;Could you fix this?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Admittedly, I did contact the administrators of our Mattermost instance but I think they&amp;rsquo;re non technical?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The response I got was akin to &amp;ldquo;It works on my machine. Have you tried Google Chrome?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a bit of fiddling, I realised that simply adding a &lt;a href=&#34;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/ublock-origin/cjpalhdlnbpafiamejdnhcphjbkeiagm?hl=en&#34;&gt;uBlock Origin&lt;/a&gt; block rule for the plugin configuration API endpoint means that Mattermost never learns what plugins exist, and so just skips on to fetching actual content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While this restricts you to using the browser, it shaves a decent 20 seconds off the startup time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honestly though, I somewhat prefer the experience as it is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Forced to be asynchronous as most useful chat platforms should be.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is the future of emergency services?</title>
      <link>https://utf9k.net/blog/future-of-emergency-services/</link>
      <description>It&#39;s surprising that the idea of an emergency service is even viable, considering how many people are doing things at any given time</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
      <author><name>Marcus Crane</name></author>
      <guid>https://utf9k.net/blog/future-of-emergency-services/</guid>
      <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, I had an onset of severe abdominal pains. I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to overreact so I called &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.health.govt.nz/your-health/services-and-support/health-care-services/healthline&#34;&gt;Healthline&lt;/a&gt; who recommended I see either my GP, or &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Emergency_department&#34;&gt;A&amp;amp;E&lt;/a&gt; within the next 6 hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shortly after I hung up, I had a pain spike bad enough to make me burst into tears. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t getting anywhere clutching my stomach on the floor so I called an ambulance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An operator took my information, said that someone would be on their way and then hung up. I waited… and waited… Just over an hour passed before I gave up and called an Uber. One just happened to be 2 minutes away, with the entire trip only taking about 10 minutes from start to finish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part of me worried they had turned up only to find me not there so I called back and asked to have the request cancelled. They did so and I asked what the state of the callout was only to find that nothing was ever dispatched due to a high callout rate in my area. Presumably based on my age and the symptoms, they figured I was at low risk?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It didn&amp;rsquo;t leave me with a good feeling or sense of security but it did get me wondering about two things: Statistics and the future of emergency services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of this article would likely have been joking about how there will probably be &amp;ldquo;Uber for Ambulances&amp;rdquo; as I often have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;new startup idea: uber for ambulances. cheaper rates than a normal ambulance unless rugby is on then it&amp;rsquo;s 6x surge prices or you&amp;rsquo;re fucked — &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/sentreh&#34;&gt;@sentreh&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There have been &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/10/01/upshot/uber-lyft-and-the-urgency-of-saving-money-on-ambulances.html&#34;&gt;a&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/carolineodonovan/taking-uber-lyft-emergency-room-legal-liabilities&#34;&gt;few&lt;/a&gt; writeups about how patients are using ridesharing services in place of ambulances and I think I understand why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www2.ku.edu/~kuwpaper/2017Papers/201708.pdf&#34;&gt;This non-peer reviewed paper&lt;/a&gt; in particular, from the University of Kansas, noted an 8% decline in ambulance callouts following the launch of Uber in each respective city measured in the study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now having said all this, there was actually an announcement this time last year for &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.uber.com/newsroom/uber-health/&#34;&gt;Uber Health&lt;/a&gt; in the US. The service is more for booking health-related rides on behalf of patients, as opposed to straight up replacing ambulances but give it enough time and I could see that extra capacity being leveraged to fill in the gaps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My second question, and one that I&amp;rsquo;m not really qualified to answer, is to do with the actual callout rates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/St_John_New_Zealand&#34;&gt;St John&lt;/a&gt; Organisation are the primary dispatcher of ambulances in New Zealand, providing emergency services to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.stjohn.org.nz/What-we-do/St-John-Ambulance-Services/&#34;&gt;nearly 90% of New Zealanders&lt;/a&gt; according to their own website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They have a handy &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.stjohn.org.nz/News--Info/Our-Performance/Response-Times/&#34;&gt;section on response times&lt;/a&gt; which links to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.health.govt.nz/new-zealand-health-system/key-health-sector-organisations-and-people/naso-national-ambulance-sector-office/emergency-ambulance-services-eas/performance-quality-and-safety/emergency-ambulance-service-national-performance-reports&#34;&gt;Ministry of Health&amp;rsquo;s Emergency Ambulance Service national performance reports&lt;/a&gt;. Look a bit closer and you&amp;rsquo;ll see &amp;ldquo;For information about St John’s performance visit the performance section of their web site.&amp;rdquo; which just leads us back to where we started!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, their annual reports contain some of the information we&amp;rsquo;re after. Let&amp;rsquo;s take the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.stjohn.org.nz/globalassets/documents/publications/annual-report/stj-annual-report_2018_lq.pdf&#34;&gt;2018 Annual report&lt;/a&gt; as an example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we jump all the way to Page 50, we can see a breakdown of numbers with 533,669 ambulance emergency calls made. Another line item mentions 480,411 patients treated or transported by ambulance officers. If we were to very roughly assume that 1 call correlated with 1 patient, that would leave 53,258 calls that are never responded to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously that&amp;rsquo;s not the whole picture. One call could be for a car crash with multiple injuries while the already deceased may not be counted as &amp;ldquo;Patients treated or transported&amp;rdquo;. Similarly, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t take into account prank calls, duplicate calls and no-show patients who can&amp;rsquo;t cancel callouts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Either way, I think it still does point out that there&amp;rsquo;s likely a chunk of callouts that never get responded to as a result of unstaffing combined with ever increasing callout numbers. It&amp;rsquo;s pretty dystopian having something like the &amp;ldquo;Gig Economy&amp;rdquo; acting as a replacement for essential services but I suppose I&amp;rsquo;ll take what I can get.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides, I never liked the attention that came with flashing lights and sirens anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Humans don&#39;t come with lore tabs</title>
      <link>https://utf9k.net/blog/lore-tabs/</link>
      <description>Stories are fascinating but speed running them is a recipe for trouble</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
      <author><name>Marcus Crane</name></author>
      <guid>https://utf9k.net/blog/lore-tabs/</guid>
      <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This post has been a long time coming because I&amp;rsquo;ve never really known how to express it. I&amp;rsquo;m not even sure I can write it properly anyway but I&amp;rsquo;m going to at least try.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently started the Xero Graduate Programme which has been amazing! As with any new position, it inevitably involves meeting a lot of new people for the first time. I&amp;rsquo;m not really here to talk about the program itself which is a story for another time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m purely talking about my own experiences struggling to interact with people properly. I figure by writing about it, even if I should fail to improve as a result, you&amp;rsquo;ll at least have an insight to how some people struggle with this kinda stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I often feel like I&amp;rsquo;m stuck in a recurring loop where I&amp;rsquo;ll meet someone that I consider to be not only interesting, but worth knowing, and so I decide &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;d like to know more about this person&amp;rdquo;. I mean, we all do it but the more I consider my past approaches, I&amp;rsquo;ve realised that I was digging for lore first, rather than getting to properly know the person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do I mean? Well, let me take a step back and explain what lore is. It&amp;rsquo;s a term that is found commonly in fictional universes such as TV series, games, comics, movies and so on. If the story and character progression of a TV series is the plot, then lore is the mythos of the characters and its world. Past battles, heroic struggles, craters left where cities once stood, ancient texts left by those past and so on. Obviously I&amp;rsquo;m not suggesting that your average person is supposed to be some kind of otherworldly being but the point is, humans don&amp;rsquo;t have lore tabs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I mean is that you can&amp;rsquo;t, and shouldn&amp;rsquo;t, be able to just learn about someone in an instant. Game of Thrones is likely a popular example of this. I haven&amp;rsquo;t watched it but I know that if I were to start, I could pour over its wiki and spend hours learning about cities, people, kingdoms, tribes and so on. For years, humans have been fascinated by good stories and lore, no matter the medium it takes, is probably the purest concentration of stories past.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actual humans - living people - may have good stories and interesting tales but you can&amp;rsquo;t just skip to the last page and find out what happens to your favourite character. At some point, you might consider learning a lot about someone would make you a better friend because you can understand their nuances. Learning what makes them tick may allow you to adapt but friendships aren&amp;rsquo;t the result of studying someone&amp;rsquo;s past. Funnily enough, they&amp;rsquo;re the result of being a part of someone&amp;rsquo;s past, which can only be done by being in the present. Ironic since it&amp;rsquo;s almost putting the two backwards but in a sense, that&amp;rsquo;s what I had been doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What leads someone to think like that? I&amp;rsquo;ve been mulling over this lately because almost all of us act out the same pattern to an extent. Biographies, literally the story of others, are a popular book category while Wikipedia has detailed articles on any celebrity you can imagine. They&amp;rsquo;re still people too like you and me so where do you draw the line? Heck, the sheer scale of public information shared by society makes it easier than ever before to scope out someone&amp;rsquo;s past. We&amp;rsquo;re the most documented group of humans in history, essentially recording our autobiographies in real time. The only deciding factor I can up with has to be intent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not what it used to be but I remembered a post from Lifehacker that I read back when, geez, I must&amp;rsquo;ve been about 14 at the time? The author was talking about Last.FM. The short of it is that you can &amp;ldquo;scrobble&amp;rdquo; music you listen to. It just records a song as listened to once you&amp;rsquo;ve hit, say 80% of the song played. Over time, you can view a history of your favourite artists, get recommendations and generally just share your taste in music. The post was talking about the Last.FM service, and specifically how the author had noted their friend would scrobble happy tracks on a good day and vice versa when things were looking bleak.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their friend was inadvertently letting on to how they truly felt without possibly giving it a second thought. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t track down the original post which is probably long gone but the author noted how it enabled them to be a better friend to an extent. I&amp;rsquo;m fairly certain that was actually the day I signed up for the service and I still use it to this day. Spotify and other popular services still have native integrations built into their clients. Perhaps it&amp;rsquo;s obvious but the same never happened for me. Who could expect such a thing with so much content floating around. Even if someone did have a look, you&amp;rsquo;d have to be consciously looking for patterns anyway. If I can&amp;rsquo;t be lucky enough to have someone who thinks like that, surely I can be that person for someone else, right? The intention is good so what could go wrong?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like most things that get out of hand, this all started small and with the best of intentions. I&amp;rsquo;ve got two past examples that quickly spiraled in different directions. I&amp;rsquo;ll leave them up for you to decide what&amp;rsquo;s good, bad and in between. Sometimes things are never so clear cut, especially in the moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I once was getting ready for a date and I was quite excited! It&amp;rsquo;s not often that I set them up and when I do, I try to put in my best efforts. I was stood up and left very confused. Not only that, I was blocked on every conceivable platform for no obvious reason. I know it&amp;rsquo;s often said but I genuinely didn&amp;rsquo;t get it. I should&amp;rsquo;ve shrugged it off but it kept eating away at me until I decided I needed to find out just to get over it. Back to what I said about biographies, she&amp;rsquo;d had a YouTube channel with a public view history. Roughly 30% of the views she watched were themed around dealing with anxiety. Part of me wish I had known that earlier so I could have been more accomodating if that&amp;rsquo;s what she needed but context matters. Here was a relative stranger that I have no right to know any more than she lets on personally. I still feel bad for her honestly even though I was the one who got burnt. Were they bad actions to take even though they had good intentions? I honestly can&amp;rsquo;t say.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was scrolling my timeline one night and came across a tweet from a teenager. He&amp;rsquo;d claimed to have just swallowed an entire bottle of medicine in a suicide attempt that he desperately wanted to undo. Rounding up an online acquaintance, we put our cursed skills to work as quick as we could. From little more than a username, we narrowed him down to a first name, nationality, gender, age estimate and state. Unfortunately it wasn&amp;rsquo;t enough specific enough that any authorities would be able to put it to use but he did end up surviving. I had previously sent him a message reassuring him since he&amp;rsquo;d disappeared offline but I never got a response.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He&amp;rsquo;s still active to this day I believe but understandably, two strangers digging up your information can be disconcering no matter the circumstance. I still feel bad about the situation, despite the outcome. As you comb through those forum posts, abandoned IRC logs and tweets, you begin to feel like you understand the person. You can almost picture how they&amp;rsquo;re thinking by what they say, and even more crucially, what they don&amp;rsquo;t. It&amp;rsquo;s like you know the person for a brief moment only to remember it&amp;rsquo;s a one way screen and they could give less of a shit about you despite the attempt. Good actions? Good intent? What&amp;rsquo;s the difference? They&amp;rsquo;re essentially the same story, right but they feel different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, what&amp;rsquo;s the point of this little exercise, and this post as a whole? The big picture of it is that realistically, what I&amp;rsquo;ve just described is a problem. I often have a problem with getting to properly know people. I&amp;rsquo;m great at learning who someone is but generally at a distance. If a group of friends are the main cast, I&amp;rsquo;m one of the extras in the background. Honestly, I probably don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;m worthy enough to be promoted to a main character in this scenario because I often struggle to see it happening. I was recently at a meetup and I felt painfully like the odd one out. You can almost read the indifference in some people&amp;rsquo;s face when you talk to them. If I&amp;rsquo;ve learnt anything over the last few years, it&amp;rsquo;s that I think I&amp;rsquo;ll always cope better being picky with this sort of stuff. Sometimes I try to be friendly and seemingly the other party gets the wrong impression that I have some kind of motive. To steal a quote from Wargames, it often feels like the only winning move is not to play.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;ve ever read Dale Carnegie&amp;rsquo;s How to Win Friends and Influence People, then good on you because I haven&amp;rsquo;t. In the book, he comes to the conclusion that for others to take a genuine interest in you, it takes little more than being interested in them. The more you ask questions of others, the more interesting they will apparently find you. Perhaps it&amp;rsquo;s true, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t say but lately I feel like mystery might be a common thread. Looking back, some of the more interesting people I&amp;rsquo;ve met have been quite illusive. That is to say, they&amp;rsquo;re never around. At that point, I have to wonder though if it&amp;rsquo;s the absence generates the mystery or if being a wanted person generates the absence. Perhaps one feeds the other and the secret is to just not give a shit and purposely be unavailable. Just rarely look at notifications and struggle to keep appointments. Slowly disappear from view until you&amp;rsquo;re all but forgotten. I&amp;rsquo;m joking of course but I wonder if there&amp;rsquo;s something to be learnt from those people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all, what have we learnt? Well, I&amp;rsquo;ve basically admitted that I may or may not be an awful person depending on how you&amp;rsquo;ve felt after taking this lengthy journey. Odds are that you&amp;rsquo;ve already made up your mind well before now if we&amp;rsquo;ve met before. Hopefully you&amp;rsquo;ve gained some insight into the meta of dealing with other people. I suppose this kind of thing comes naturally but I feel like I missed a memo somewhere. Either way, the first step is admitting something is wrong. Once you do that, hopefully it should be more straightfoward to progress and become a better person. Perhaps you can let me know how I get on?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now if you&amp;rsquo;ll excuse me, I have to go and return some videotapes.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
