<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>utf9k</title>
    <link>https://utf9k.net/tags/mystery/</link>
    <description>Posts from utf9k</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <author>
      <name>Marcus Crane</name>
      <email>marcus@utf9k.net</email>
    </author>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2022 23:35:00 +1300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://utf9k.net/tags/mystery/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Do demo iPads have a canonical owner?</title>
      <link>https://utf9k.net/blog/ipad-canonical-owner/</link>
      <description>In which we investigate whether the demo content loaded onto iPads is owned a single fictional person</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2022 23:35:00 +1300</pubDate>
      <author><name>Marcus Crane</name></author>
      <guid>https://utf9k.net/blog/ipad-canonical-owner/</guid>
      <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A few years ago, I ordered a 4th generation Apple iPad Air and the store I purchased it from accidentally sent me a demo unit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a fully working iPad but it came preloaded with a number of dummy items such as a five calendars, a handful of documents and acres of photos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can see these in any store but generally, you never get a chance to spend any length of time with them so making the most of this opportunity, I took a full backup of the device before resetting it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;storedisplay.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;A photo of an iPad Pro set up for display inside of a Noel Leeming store. Visible on the iPad is the Photos app set to the time period spanning 17 - 25th July 2019&#34;  /&gt;&lt;p&gt;A few days later, the store got in contact with me and requested that I return it back to them since it wasn&amp;rsquo;t meant to be dispatched. They didn&amp;rsquo;t have any other units on hand so I ended up getting a refund instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I figured it might be of some interest to someone so I &lt;a href=&#34;https://archive.org/details/i-pad-demo-backup&#34;&gt;uploaded a copy of the demo materials to the Internet Archive&lt;/a&gt; and never got around to doing anything more until now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Something that I had wondered was if any of the content in the device was actually intertwined or if it was just a random helping of documents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The short answer is that it is mostly just random items but each category of item tends to have been created from the point of view of a single person which is kind of neat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll be doing a brief rundown of what I found and what I could infer from the demo content about each fictional person as best as I can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the data is meaningless outside of the demo unit such as Photos which were grouped such as two images that were under the &amp;ldquo;Selfies&amp;rdquo; category but I can&amp;rsquo;t recreate that information with the photos themselves so this post can&amp;rsquo;t be as extensive as it could have been but ah well, I mainly want to get this post off of my project backlog once and for all!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;calendars&#34;&gt;Calendars&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ll start with the juiciest of all the categories first since the rest are fairly light on detail. We can infer quite a bit from the calendar from the various locations attached to events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;calendar.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;A screenshot of the macOS Calendar app visible on the author&amp;amp;rsquo;s computer. 11 events are visible across five different calendars.&#34;  /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Loaded onto the demo unit were 5 calendars which are available as &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ICalendar&#34;&gt;ICS&lt;/a&gt; exports for browsing with any Calendar client.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As far as I can tell, the calendar events consist entirely of recurring events which makes sense for a demo unit which may sit around for a number of years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The five calendars available are called &lt;code&gt;Kids&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Personal&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Recreation&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Training&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Work&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll mention in advance that a number of locations are mentioned in the calendar entries which are mostly real places around California so I dig into those a little bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ll work through them in order:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;kids&#34;&gt;Kids&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;kids.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;A screenshot of the macOS Calendar app visible on the author&amp;amp;rsquo;s computer. The Kids calendar is selected.&#34;  /&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are only 3 events on the kids calendar which are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adam&amp;rsquo;s Piano lesson from 3:30pm - 4:30pm every Tuesday&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ellie&amp;rsquo;s Soccer Game from 6:00pm - 8:00pm every Wednesday&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adam&amp;rsquo;s Soccer Game from 11:00am - 2:00pm on every 5th Saturday&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can infer that this person has two kids: Adam and Ellie. Both play Soccer and Adam plays the piano.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The description for &lt;code&gt;Ellie&#39;s Soccer Game&lt;/code&gt; mentioned &lt;code&gt;At Mount Tiburon High School - back field on the left.&lt;/code&gt; in the description for the event but as far as I can tell, there isn&amp;rsquo;t a Mount Tiburon High School.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tiburon,_California&#34;&gt;Tiburon&lt;/a&gt; is a real town in California that has a Mount Tiburon Road but no high school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, Tiburon is apparently home to &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tiburon,_California#Schools&#34;&gt;St. Hilary School&lt;/a&gt; which is an &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.apple.com/nz/education/k12/apple-distinguished-schools/&#34;&gt;Apple Distinguished School&lt;/a&gt; but it&amp;rsquo;s probably a coincidence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;personal&#34;&gt;Personal&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;personal.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;A screenshot of the macOS Calendar app visible on the author&amp;amp;rsquo;s computer. The Personal calendar is selected.&#34;  /&gt;&lt;p&gt;This calendar is home to a few generic events such as &amp;ldquo;Pay Bills&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Doctor&amp;rsquo;s Appointment&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a number of lunch and coffee catchups and they tend to be at real places:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lunch with Pablo at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.michaelmina.net/restaurants/&#34;&gt;Michael Mina&lt;/a&gt; every 2 weeks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lunch with Becky at &lt;a href=&#34;https://yanksing.com/&#34;&gt;Yank Sing&lt;/a&gt; every 7 weeks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lunch with Mum at &lt;a href=&#34;https://hoodline.com/2017/09/french-bistro-south-park-cafe-to-bid-adieu/&#34;&gt;Bistro - South Park&lt;/a&gt; every 4 weeks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are some other catchups but none of them feature any locations&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;recreation&#34;&gt;Recreation&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;recreation.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;A screenshot of the macOS Calendar app visible on the author&amp;amp;rsquo;s computer. The Recreation calendar is selected.&#34;  /&gt;&lt;p&gt;This calendar is what it says on the tin and features a number of locations as well:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lunch with Lucy at &lt;a href=&#34;https://yanksing.com/&#34;&gt;Yank Sing&lt;/a&gt; every 3 weeks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bowling at Biltmore Lanes every month.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find any information on Biltmore Lanes if that&amp;rsquo;s a real place.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Neighbourhood Council at Community Centre on the 4th month of every Sunday
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The community centre in question is not named but perhaps you could triangulate one by cross-referencing the locations the calendar owner visits?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yoga at &lt;a href=&#34;https://2ndstreetgym.com/&#34;&gt;2nd Street Gym&lt;/a&gt; every 3 weeks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Brunch with Mindy at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.zaziesf.com/&#34;&gt;Zazie&lt;/a&gt; on the 1st Sunday of every month&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tennis with Katy at the 4th Street Courts every 3 weeks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;training&#34;&gt;Training&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;training.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;A screenshot of the macOS Calendar app visible on the author&amp;amp;rsquo;s computer. The Training calendar is selected.&#34;  /&gt;&lt;p&gt;I expected this calendar to be full of gym sessions but instead it&amp;rsquo;s a work calendar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not sure who the training is in reference to, or if this calendar is even accurately named since it seems like a bunch of business meetings more than anything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve got the following events:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Design Team Staff Meeting: &amp;ldquo;To review designs for this week&amp;rsquo;s exec meetng and discuss remaining designs needed.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Review Graphic Design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Review Presentation with Susan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Project Planning Meeting: &amp;ldquo;To discuss project plan and review milestones and deliverables&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None of this appears to be training unless it&amp;rsquo;s training for design team members perhaps?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From this, we can infer that this person is perhaps some sort of product manager?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;work&#34;&gt;Work&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;work.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;A screenshot of the macOS Calendar app visible on the author&amp;amp;rsquo;s computer. The Work calendar is selected.&#34;  /&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is definitely the fullest calendar with a number of business meetings and catchups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve got the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Weekly Team Meeting: &amp;ldquo;To discuss project status and deliverables. Please bring status on each deliverable due this week.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conference Call with Exec Team&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Budget Review: &amp;ldquo;To review budget plans for upcoming projects&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Design Review&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Team meeting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contract Review with Allison&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Executive Briefing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Expense Review: &amp;ldquo;To review this expenses to date and discuss plans for the next phase of the project.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Meeting with Sales Team&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s all very generic as to what this person&amp;rsquo;s role is but of course, this is all stuff designed to be glanced at for a couple of seconds if at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s also a monthly entry for &amp;ldquo;Pancake Breakfast&amp;rdquo; at &amp;ldquo;St. Mary&amp;rsquo;s&amp;rdquo; but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find any such place in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/San_Francisco_Bay_Area&#34;&gt;Bay Area&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;contacts&#34;&gt;Contacts&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are 238 contact entries provided in two formats: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/VCard&#34;&gt;VCF&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://fileinfo.com/extension/abbu&#34;&gt;ABBU&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;contacts.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;A screenshot of the macOS Contacts app visible on the author&amp;amp;rsquo;s computer. A contact entry for Shota Aoyagi is selected. They have an iCloud email and allegedly live in Rochester, New York. Their contact card has a stock photo.&#34;  /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The vast majority of contacts have addressed all across the United States of America with a handful that have addresses in Australia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given I live in New Zealand, I&amp;rsquo;m guessing that demo units have a handful of regionalised entries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I couldn&amp;rsquo;t determine any link between the contact entries and other categories ie; no one from the Contacts list appears in any of the Calendar entries or in the Summer Garden Party attendee list that we&amp;rsquo;ll be covering later on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That said, I did google a number of the names and they all appear to be Apple employees in some capacity but with stock avatars and made up contact details of course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;These were loaded as &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Notes_(Apple)&#34;&gt;Apple Notes&lt;/a&gt; but there&amp;rsquo;s no standard format so they were all exported as PDFs. They&amp;rsquo;re mostly intact but some formatting got mangled in the process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;notes.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;A screenshot of the macOS Preview app showing a PDF. The PDF is an exported Apple Note showing a sketch for a treehouse. The note is titled &amp;amp;ldquo;Jake&amp;amp;rsquo;s treehouse!!&amp;amp;rdquo;&#34;  /&gt;&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a note for &lt;code&gt;After-school activities for Jake&lt;/code&gt; containing a checklist of sports so presumably this person is helping their son to decide on a sport. Interestingly, one of the entries is &amp;ldquo;Footy&amp;rdquo; which is a slang term for &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Australian_rules_football&#34;&gt;Australian rules football&lt;/a&gt; so I guess this note is localised a little bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems this person is building a back porch based on the &lt;code&gt;Back porch dimensions&lt;/code&gt; note with another title &lt;code&gt;Garden proposal from our architect&lt;/code&gt; which details where to lay out plants around their &amp;ldquo;back patio&amp;rdquo;. I would note that porch isn&amp;rsquo;t really a term used in &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Oceania&#34;&gt;Oceania&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keeping with the renovation theme, we also have notes for &lt;code&gt;Trees/Plants for front garden&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Things to do for salsa garden&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;New dishwasher options&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Living room remodel ideas&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Kitchen&lt;/code&gt; (renovation) and &lt;code&gt;Get at hardware store&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I noted before about the mention of &amp;ldquo;Footy&amp;rdquo;, there are a few holiday planning notes that are all in America. The note &lt;code&gt;Ideas for US reunion w/ Dave and crew&lt;/code&gt; has an entry for New York City that reads as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all met here and we all love this city, but maybe not the best choice for a week of catching up over old times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The use of the term &amp;ldquo;this&amp;rdquo; implies that the person writing these notes currently lives in New York City but a few notes contradict this idea because they feature measurements in centimetres. America is one of the few countries that &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/United_States_customary_units&#34;&gt;doesn&amp;rsquo;t make use of the metric system&lt;/a&gt; so this doesn&amp;rsquo;t quite add up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few holiday notes seem to center around California which definitely lines up with the general Apple-adjacent locations that appear through the demo unit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A note titled &lt;code&gt;Soccer practise times&lt;/code&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; contains practice times for Zoe and Ella who, in addition to Jake, are presumably the three children of the author of these notes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The practice times mentioned take place at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.santaritaschool.org/santaritaes/6993-Address-Directions.html&#34;&gt;Santa Rita School&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.covingtonschool.org/ces/4740-About.html&#34;&gt;Covington School&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.losaltosca.gov/recreation/page/rosita-park&#34;&gt;Rosita Park&lt;/a&gt; which are all real places in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.losaltosca.gov/&#34;&gt;Los Altos, California&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you check on a map, Los Altos is a short drive from Cupertino, which is home to &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Apple_Park&#34;&gt;Apple&amp;rsquo;s donut headquarters&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond the above, most of the notes don&amp;rsquo;t really tell us much about the author besides the fact that they have three kids it appears.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;numbers&#34;&gt;Numbers&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is a planning spreadsheet for a Summer Garden Party available as a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Numbers_(spreadsheet)&#34;&gt;Numbers&lt;/a&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;numbers.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;A screenshot of the macOS Preview app displaying a preview of a Number spreadsheet. Visible is a planning document for a garden party which lists a number of hosts and guests. A number of tasks are planned to be done between June and July. There are 4 sheets in total.&#34;  /&gt;&lt;p&gt;There isn&amp;rsquo;t much to say about this other than it&amp;rsquo;s a planning document for a party. I cross-referenced the names with the Contacts entries and while there were some shared names, I don&amp;rsquo;t think they were the same people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing I was able to infer was from a section on the &amp;ldquo;Budget&amp;rdquo; sheet titled &amp;ldquo;Useful Contacts&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It lists a number of party-related businesses such as &amp;ldquo;Joe the Juggler&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;True Cook&amp;rdquo; catering. All of the phone numbers feature area codes from around the New York area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;pages&#34;&gt;Pages&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is a document on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Leaning_Tower_of_Pisa&#34;&gt;Leaning Tower of Pisa&lt;/a&gt; created with &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pages_(word_processor)&#34;&gt;Pages&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s available as a &lt;code&gt;.pages&lt;/code&gt; file as well as a PDF export.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;pages.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;A screenshot of the macOS Preview app displaying a preview of a Pages document. Visible is a page about the Leaning Tower of Pisa. It talks about the history of the tower and how it wasn&amp;amp;rsquo;t always leaning.&#34;  /&gt;&lt;p&gt;It appears to be a school report since it&amp;rsquo;s relatively accessible and light on details. The cover page says that it&amp;rsquo;s by &amp;ldquo;Mariana Lin&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a &amp;ldquo;Mariana Lin&amp;rdquo; in the Contacts list but I can&amp;rsquo;t say whether there&amp;rsquo;s any relation since we know that the names features don&amp;rsquo;t align with the contact details, being Apple employees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;slides&#34;&gt;Slides&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is a presentation on &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Yellowstone_National_Park&#34;&gt;Yellowstone National Park&lt;/a&gt; created with &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Keynote_(presentation_software)&#34;&gt;Keynote&lt;/a&gt; and available as a &lt;code&gt;.key&lt;/code&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;slides.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;A screenshot of the macOS Preview app displaying a preview of a Keynote slide. Visible is a picture of Old Faithful, a geyser at Yellowstone National Park. The slide talks about what makes geysers spew water.&#34;  /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The presentation is attributed to Jamie Wong, Lauren Kerr and Greg Novick, none of whom appear in the Contacts listing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I assume it&amp;rsquo;s also meant to be a school presentation as it&amp;rsquo;s pretty light on detail. I didn&amp;rsquo;t check if there are any presenter notes but I&amp;rsquo;m guessing there probably aren&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, running &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Strings_(Unix)&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;strings&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; across the file throws up a reference to &lt;code&gt;Data/GettyImages-451901451-8851.mov&lt;/code&gt; so it might include a video which would explain the beefy 236.5MB file size. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t tell where it features from using Preview and I don&amp;rsquo;t currently have Keynote installed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;maps&#34;&gt;Maps&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The installed version of Apple Maps contained 25 locations saved which were exported as a &lt;a href=&#34;https://fileinfo.com/extension/webloc&#34;&gt;webloc&lt;/a&gt; file that can be imported into Apple Maps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;maps.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;A screenshot of the macOS Maps app. A map collection titled &amp;amp;ldquo;iPad Demo Unit Places&amp;amp;rdquo; is selected on the right. Visible in the main window is North America which depicts a number of bookmarked locations.&#34;  /&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can actually view all of the locations on the web &lt;a href=&#34;https://guides.apple.com/?ug=CglNeSBQbGFjZXMSDgiuTRCvqe7D1Ny%2B0c8BEg0Irk0Qz%2FvZ4ZWbx9tBEg4Irk0Q07KFg%2F%2FQ%2BrnQARIOCK5NEMeAvZu8zOeUtwESDQiuTRDI4rigp6nsmwoSDgiuTRDo%2Fqe%2FvObuqOkBEg0Irk0Q5K%2FmsO64yJlxEg0Irk0Q8ayI64Pohv4OEg0Irk0Q09rW7Kq%2BiJhkEg4Irk0Q4IWIktWzuN%2FrARIOCK5NEN%2FqnrONnc3%2FtQESDQiuTRDDnK%2Ffxefylm4SDgiuTRDO%2BLmCgoX4hIkBEg0Irk0QlqLPz%2B%2FCqu8kEg4Irk0Qxqnl%2FNTUhb3KARINCK5NEOjYh9WIyM7IQBINCK5NEMWgq%2BbIqN%2FzBBINCK5NELWBwaT3lZ7lFRINCK5NEOa0h4ye9qb3IhIOCK5NEL3vkc6h0JrS4wESDQiuTRCJidXtgZHQ4gQSDgiuTRCl45zH%2F5%2BYqfwBEg0Irk0Qs6KWyKqUs94NEg0Irk0Qy47O5vuQt5BgEg4Irk0Q8tnK55HulOvfARIOCK5NELKK3MOW3YeIhgE%3D&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; which is the link contained by the &lt;code&gt;webloc&lt;/code&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;photos&#34;&gt;Photos&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;As mentioned at the start, there are a great deal of photos but a lot of useful metadata requires them to be loaded into Photos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;photos.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;A screenshot of the macOS Finder app. Visible is a photo of a dog with metadata about the photo visible on the right side.&#34;  /&gt;&lt;p&gt;They all have their original metadata which is interesting since there are a range of iOS devices used to take photos, not that I could ever take photos that nice with my own phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are 437 photos in total although upon a quick skim, there are actually a couple of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/QuickTime_File_Format&#34;&gt;mov&lt;/a&gt; videos as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Overall, this post wasn&amp;rsquo;t particularly interesting to create but I figure it&amp;rsquo;s useful to capture since the odds of getting a demo unit are probably not that great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each category of file tends to have been created from the point of view of a single person so it&amp;rsquo;d be interesting to know how much detail went into determining each persona in order to inform what the content should look like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also wonder what team would be in charge of preloading fake content onto a device. I guess it would fall into the realm of marketing?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;d be kind funny telling your parents like &amp;ldquo;Yeah, I make fake content for iPads&amp;rdquo; or something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, as mentioned, I&amp;rsquo;m glad to finally cross this project off my list and delete these files from my desktop so they&amp;rsquo;ll stop judging me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once again, you can download all of the files referenced in this post &lt;a href=&#34;https://archive.org/details/i-pad-demo-backup&#34;&gt;over on the Internet Archive&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The typo is part of the title&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
