<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>utf9k</title>
    <link>https://utf9k.net/tags/phones/</link>
    <description>Posts from utf9k</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <author>
      <name>Marcus Crane</name>
      <email>marcus@utf9k.net</email>
    </author>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 13:02:46 +1300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://utf9k.net/tags/phones/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>We are all that person who reads a book while walking</title>
      <link>https://utf9k.net/blog/walking-while-reading/</link>
      <description>Honestly, this post is weird and dumb. I wouldn&#39;t recommend it.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 13:02:46 +1300</pubDate>
      <author><name>Marcus Crane</name></author>
      <guid>https://utf9k.net/blog/walking-while-reading/</guid>
      <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;There is a person who lives in my general area that I&amp;rsquo;ve spotted two or three times in the almost three years that I have lived at my flat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He has a book open and reads it, while walking and for the most part, seemingly not paying any attention to where he is going.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It feels entirely ridiculous and comical so it&amp;rsquo;s definitely noticeable whenever I do spot him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That behaviour is something I think I&amp;rsquo;ve seen before at school where you would have that one kid seemingly glued to a book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How that knowledge is used is beyond me since they never seem to do much else besides reading but that&amp;rsquo;s besides the point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As ridiculous as their actions seem, we&amp;rsquo;re effectively all that person now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anytime we get the urge to see what new chat message has arrived or whip out a device to flick through a music playlist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s really just the same behaviour but without the persistence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I probably never learned anything from quickly skimming my &amp;ldquo;Liked Songs&amp;rdquo; on Spotify while waiting for a traffic light though.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
