<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>utf9k</title>
    <link>https://utf9k.net/tags/timemanagement/</link>
    <description>Posts from utf9k</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <author>
      <name>Marcus Crane</name>
      <email>marcus@utf9k.net</email>
    </author>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Jul 2021 22:53:00 +1300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://utf9k.net/tags/timemanagement/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Time Dilation</title>
      <link>https://utf9k.net/blog/time-dilation/</link>
      <description>Historically, I am often late to a bunch of things even though I plan ahead some of the time</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jul 2021 22:53:00 +1300</pubDate>
      <author><name>Marcus Crane</name></author>
      <guid>https://utf9k.net/blog/time-dilation/</guid>
      <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A more accurate title would probably be something like &amp;ldquo;Time Inflation&amp;rdquo; but I think &amp;ldquo;Time Dilation&amp;rdquo; sounds cooler.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whenever I&amp;rsquo;m planning a trip anywhere, often just across town, I tend to tack on an extra portion of time. Usually just 10 or 15 minutes as a bit of a buffer and depending on the mode of transport, it tends to get eaten up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trouble is that I don&amp;rsquo;t really go back and re-evaluate how long it takes to get places. The next time I plan a trip, I tack on an extra portion of time. Usually just 10 or 15 minutes and&amp;hellip; hold on a minute, didn&amp;rsquo;t we already account for it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure there are some things that I just don&amp;rsquo;t even bother doing at all because I&amp;rsquo;ve built this big time sink out of it when in reality, it won&amp;rsquo;t take very long at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember taking the bus somewhere not that long ago and I was surprised that it only took a few minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, yes, buses like most vehicles are quite fast on land but I guess my perception of time got a bit mangled somewhere along the track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The irony of this of course, is that I waste large swathes of time checking the same five websites for updates, which I didn&amp;rsquo;t really class as procrastination until recently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s not really a moral to the story or anything like that but re-evaluating what you think you know from time to time can never hurt.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
