<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>utf9k</title>
    <link>https://utf9k.net/tags/reliability/</link>
    <description>Posts from utf9k</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <author>
      <name>Marcus Crane</name>
      <email>marcus@utf9k.net</email>
    </author>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 12:01:00 +1300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://utf9k.net/tags/reliability/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Day Two</title>
      <link>https://utf9k.net/blog/day-two/</link>
      <description>Thoughts as I enter the third job of my career in the software industry</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 12:01:00 +1300</pubDate>
      <author><name>Marcus Crane</name></author>
      <guid>https://utf9k.net/blog/day-two/</guid>
      <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve recently started as a Senior Site Reliability Engineer at &lt;a href=&#34;https://lightspeedhq.com/&#34;&gt;Lightspeed&lt;/a&gt; which means that it&amp;rsquo;s time for the sequel to &lt;a href=&#34;https://utf9k.net/blog/day-one&#34;&gt;Day One&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the uninitiated, I write a new post summing up the excitement and concerns I have whenever I start a new job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not actually sure if I&amp;rsquo;ve ever explicitly noted that this is intended to be an ongoing series but yeah, ideally I write a new entry every time I start a new job going forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea is that I can look back and laugh at how much I did or didn&amp;rsquo;t know. I realise that from the shoes of a beginner, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to assume that long timers are magically gifted or Just Knew It All so in the event I make it somewhere interesting, this generally serves as proof that I had my doubts along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m actually quite overdue with this entry since I&amp;rsquo;m a little over a week into my new job already. I&amp;rsquo;ll probably keep it kind of brief as well since I keep staying up late&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; but I did make a couple of quick notes that I&amp;rsquo;ll try to address.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, let&amp;rsquo;s get started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;interviewing&#34;&gt;Interviewing&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I actually don&amp;rsquo;t mind interviewing so much these days but I do dread the idea of getting some overly technical, google-esque interview. I never took computer science&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref1:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; so if you ask me about B-tree&amp;rsquo;s or whatever then I&amp;rsquo;m out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a matter of fact, an interview prior to the ones with Lightspeed had me trying to write a sudoku solver. I gave it a crack but I didn&amp;rsquo;t have much to show so 10 minutes before I end, I just ended it early to save myself the humiliation. That said, I pretty confidently said that I don&amp;rsquo;t enjoy this stuff, I&amp;rsquo;m comfortable saying as much and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t reflect what I do day to day anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, I got to show a bit of everything across the stack in the Lightspeed interview with even a bit of frontend polish just for kicks :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It definitely wasn&amp;rsquo;t required but I opted to spend a bit of time on it. It&amp;rsquo;s good practice for sprucing up my website anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-first-day&#34;&gt;My first day&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;These posts don&amp;rsquo;t generally show when I&amp;rsquo;ve started but it&amp;rsquo;s probably a bit more appropriate (and relevant) of a timespan as my career progresses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had a poke around a bunch of Slack channels and was in two minds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly: wow, there&amp;rsquo;s some really cool best practice stuff going on. Secondly: Ahh geez, everyone is definitely going to be smarter than me and doing well crafted stuff while I&amp;rsquo;m super rusty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thankfully everyone is really nice and the onboarding has been pretty comprehensive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;slos&#34;&gt;SLOs&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Funnily enough, I saw a bunch of SLO monitors and my eyes probably dilated a bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.xero.com/nz/&#34;&gt;Xero&lt;/a&gt;, my team helped push the introduction of SLOs and I was in the SLO space for the better part of a year and a half and I still feel like I&amp;rsquo;ve forgotten all of it in some capacity, haha.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s really stupid like I&amp;rsquo;ve run 3 part workshops on SLOs + alerting, helped teams instrument their products and my brain is still like &amp;ldquo;I&amp;quot;m very unqualified in this space&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m sure this happens with most every domain anyway. Once I get back into it and brush up on source material again, I&amp;rsquo;m sure I&amp;rsquo;ll remember all the niche details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still such at math, and by extension statistics and what not though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Realistically, I&amp;rsquo;m probably just scared that people will ask me questions on the spot I won&amp;rsquo;t have the answers to, as if that&amp;rsquo;s how it would go down. I also have an entire team I&amp;rsquo;m part of so that&amp;rsquo;s a dumb story to tell yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;work-life-balance&#34;&gt;Work life balance&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This time around, I&amp;rsquo;m definitely focusing on clocking in and out near enough on time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s not to say I dislike my job, quite the opposite in fact. Thinking that the more hours you do magically correlates to more productivity is a lie. Productivity in general is a lie anyway. I have enough green cubes on Github without even trying, thank you very much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My thoughts on this currently would just be a regurgitation of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.oliverburkeman.com/books&#34;&gt;Four Thousand Weeks&lt;/a&gt; by Oliver Burkeman.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It looks like a self help book but it&amp;rsquo;s not. Just a reminder that always striving towards things, for the sake of &amp;ldquo;productivity&amp;rdquo;, is not a good idea generally. It&amp;rsquo;s worth a read!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;job-titles&#34;&gt;Job titles&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;It took me about a good week or so to put the &amp;ldquo;Senior&amp;rdquo; prefix in my bio and even then, I self-deprecatingly tacked &amp;ldquo;(allegedly)&amp;rdquo; on the end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think of myself as a Junior Senior, in that I just acquired this title but I guess it was bestowed upon me by passing a test so I guess I earned it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I dunno, I feel the same and I often forget that I&amp;rsquo;ve quote unquote made it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I try not to think about it and remember that there&amp;rsquo;s a whole team I&amp;rsquo;m part of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-team&#34;&gt;The team&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;They&amp;rsquo;re all really nice people that I can&amp;rsquo;t fault or have any reservations about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to consciously be a little bit more myself by bringing the sillier aspects to work such as my &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kumamon&#34;&gt;Kumamon&lt;/a&gt; obsession.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an example, I really enjoy Kumamon but even more, I find the contrast of &amp;ldquo;an industry professional&amp;rdquo; being a big fan of a cute Japanese bear even funnier. I imagine it&amp;rsquo;s weirdly jarring but I also like that it forcefully breaks any illusion of being unapproachable or overly serious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, my less serious aspects like shitposting people (although never punching down or sideways) via DMs have ended up being helpful for bridging teams who don&amp;rsquo;t communicate so easily. You can get to know individuals and figure out how to build ties with common elements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone can equally laugh at my Kumamon obsession while knowing that I&amp;rsquo;m in on the joke for example. Maybe it helps ultimately build a squillion dollar product that ultimately would have fallen apart if things were too serious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I dunno, I just want to build useful software and learn things anyway. Getting too invested into any single business, that may ultimately collapse at the whim of a newly-installed post-IPO board, is a bit of a mistake waiting to happen so just enjoy it while it lasts :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;now-what&#34;&gt;Now what&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m still onboarding and perhaps I&amp;rsquo;ll have more to write about career stuff. I think I&amp;rsquo;ll be pretty happy here for a while and I&amp;rsquo;ve got quite a bit to learn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With lockdown again here in New Zealand and my &lt;a href=&#34;https://utf9k.net/blog/ride-the-curve/&#34;&gt;brief health issues earlier this year&lt;/a&gt;, I had purposely decided not to think about work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, I was invited by the recruiter to interview so I never really plan to work here, it all came as quite a surprise!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The more technical posts I&amp;rsquo;ve written, such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://utf9k.net/blog/conditional-gitconfig/&#34;&gt;Conditionally setting your gitconfig&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://utf9k.net/blog/wsl2-vhd-issue/&#34;&gt;Fixing a WSL2 VHD conversion issue&lt;/a&gt;, continue to gain quite a bit of traffic which is interesting since I don&amp;rsquo;t do very much promotion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have some vague intention to dig through manpages and what not to see what other niche things I can dig up. I don&amp;rsquo;t intend to turn this site into some sort of &amp;ldquo;Top 5 Git Commands&amp;rdquo; hellhole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given that a few people reached out to me as a result, I&amp;rsquo;m aware that more than a few seem to have gotten real value out of problems that I was just solving for myself ultimately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://utf9k.net/questions&#34;&gt;questions&lt;/a&gt; section is still the place to go for brief, niche snippets but I would like to do some deep dives in future if anything useful comes out of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whatever, I&amp;rsquo;m just rambling at this point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until next time, see ya.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unrelated to work, just doomscrolling Twitter too much.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref1:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twitter, could you please fix your image servers?</title>
      <link>https://utf9k.net/blog/twitter-image-servers-2021/</link>
      <description>Throughout the year of 2021, I have run into a number of issues with Twitter&#39;s image servers</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 12:18:00 +1300</pubDate>
      <author><name>Marcus Crane</name></author>
      <guid>https://utf9k.net/blog/twitter-image-servers-2021/</guid>
      <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;For anyone who knows me, it&amp;rsquo;s no surprise that I&amp;rsquo;m horribly addicted to &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;. I joined back in 2009&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and I&amp;rsquo;ve fallen into more &lt;a href=&#34;https://utf9k.net/blog/automation-right/&#34;&gt;technical rabbit holes&lt;/a&gt; than I care to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a Twitter user who is Very Online, I love to theorise about why services go wrong and poke fun at corporations but as an &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Site_reliability_engineering&#34;&gt;SRE&lt;/a&gt; myself, I find it very difficult to direct blame at people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be clear, I&amp;rsquo;ll be talking about Twitter in the brand/persona sense and not as a reflection of the many people who I&amp;rsquo;m sure work tirelessly behind the scenes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some might say they&amp;rsquo;re one in the same but my general principle is that taking aim at the marketing facade is fair game while the people themselves are off limits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not that we&amp;rsquo;ve addressed that, I feel like the Twitter &amp;ldquo;experience&amp;rdquo; has been degraded for a couple of months now with no real acknowledgement that I can see. In short, I&amp;rsquo;ve seen Twitter DMs intermittently fail to load, images being corrupted upon upload and &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/wongmjane/status/1440428582308757507&#34;&gt;replies failing to load&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll be walking through the former two issues as they&amp;rsquo;ve been plaguing both myself and some friends the most.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes down to it, I&amp;rsquo;m nothing but a simple armchair critic who doesn&amp;rsquo;t have any real recourse in this abstract digital &amp;ldquo;customer support&amp;rdquo; hell we&amp;rsquo;ve constructed for ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides trying to raise awareness publically by writing this post, I have absolutely no idea if this has any traction internally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With all that out of the way, let&amp;rsquo;s have a look at what has been going on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;twitter-dm-images-failing-to-load&#34;&gt;Twitter DM images failing to load&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This one has been bugging me and some Twitter mutuals for at least a couple of months now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What happens is that intermittently, images will fail to load inside of direct messages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Often times, it isn&amp;rsquo;t that every image fails to load but one or two that have been recently uploaded. In hindsight, it may be that they all fail to load but prior images are loaded from cache now that I think about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It leads to frustrating discussions like this&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;twitter-dm-huge-l.png&#34; alt=&#34;A Twitter direct message where the author posts an image that fails to load and the recipient says &amp;amp;ldquo;huge L the image isn&amp;amp;rsquo;t loading&amp;amp;rdquo;.&#34;  /&gt;&lt;p&gt;and this&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;twitter-dm-alt-text.png&#34; alt=&#34;A Twitter direct message where the author receives an image that fails to load, asks &amp;amp;ldquo;got any alt text?&amp;amp;rdquo; and the other person responds with an accessibility style description of what is in the image. The tone of the interaction is one of lighthearted humour.&#34;  /&gt;&lt;p&gt;and this&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;twitter-dm-revenue.png&#34; alt=&#34;A Twitter direct message where the author receives an image that fails to load and responds with &amp;amp;ldquo;Guess who has $3 billion in revenue but still can&amp;amp;rsquo;t display photos in DMs :)&amp;amp;rdquo;&#34;  /&gt;&lt;p&gt;It happened again just the other day and I did a little poking around. It seems that &lt;code&gt;ton.twitter.com&lt;/code&gt;, the image server used for DMs&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; times out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;timeout.png&#34; alt=&#34;A screenshot of a terminal window with two curl commands. The first is requesting an image link over http port 80 in verbose mode. It responds as expected, with the content being a redirect to https. The second command is the prior link but accessed via https and it fails with a timeout.&#34;  /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Upon closer inspection, only Port 80 (http) appears to be open with redirects to Port 443 (https) failing as there is no such port open based on a quick scan using &lt;code&gt;nmap&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s pretty frustrating and I&amp;rsquo;ve actually resorted to DMing on other platforms because of how unstable this can get at times!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;images-being-mulched&#34;&gt;Images being mulched&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;For a period of about 2 weeks, images with transparency such as macOS screenshots were being absolutely destroyed upon upload.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/benedictevans/status/1439536308326645767&#34;&gt;@benedictevans has since set their account to private so here&amp;rsquo;s a direct link if you follow them&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ll see it looks like someone took the spray can from MS Paint and went to town on the edges of the image. That is supposed to be a nice crisp drop shadow!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-dnt=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;well now, apparently the logitech client i installed has attempted to communicate with discord &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/Uq0T1jwMYQ&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/Uq0T1jwMYQ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Marcus (@sentreh) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/sentreh/status/1436092048914796545?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;September 9, 2021&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While this appears to have been fixed recently, it was also not acknowledged as far as I can tell. Just kind of weirdly broken in plain sight for days on end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;closing-thoughts&#34;&gt;Closing thoughts&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;It doesn&amp;rsquo;t take too much to conclude that these are both image related issues which is interesting but it would be a logical leap to conclude that there is any relation between the image processing pipeline and the DM image server so any further speculation would be just that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned before, I don&amp;rsquo;t want to point fingers at any people but I will say that it frustrated me to no end seeing no acknowlegement of this happening continually.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead, right in the middle of those two transparency mulched images, what I experienced was &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/TwitterEng&#34;&gt;@TwitterEng&lt;/a&gt; was talking about mechanical keyboards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-dnt=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Today, we&amp;#39;re talking about switches... keyboard switches ⌨️&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Choose your fighter. When it comes to the best tactile response, which clickety-clack rules them all?&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;We&amp;#39;re loving TTC Bluish Whites 👀&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Engineering (@XEng) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/XEng/status/1437857022444138496?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;September 14, 2021&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m being a bit flippant mind you since it can be true that one team is doing community building while another is working on technical issues of course but at the same time, the optics of it don&amp;rsquo;t look great as someone experiencing this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, really all I want is to be able to use DMs again reliably!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead, I can&amp;rsquo;t help but feel that we&amp;rsquo;re probably going to get the ability to use &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/TheSmarmyBum/status/1443259893411049475&#34;&gt;an NFT as an avatar&lt;/a&gt; or whatever else is cooking over there sooner than a fix :(&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a few years, I&amp;rsquo;ll have been on Twitter longer than I&amp;rsquo;ve been off it (ie; before I registered/before it existed)&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As far as I can tell, &lt;code&gt;ton&lt;/code&gt; is used for DMs while &lt;code&gt;pbs&lt;/code&gt; is used for the public timeline?&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You can always count on sales</title>
      <link>https://utf9k.net/blog/you-can-always-count-on-sales/</link>
      <description>Complete system downtime won&#39;t stop the sales team from making a buck</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 18:23:00 +1300</pubDate>
      <author><name>Marcus Crane</name></author>
      <guid>https://utf9k.net/blog/you-can-always-count-on-sales/</guid>
      <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;For any readers who weren&amp;rsquo;t aware, &lt;a href=&#34;https://status.azure.com&#34;&gt;Microsoft Azure&lt;/a&gt; suffered from a &lt;a href=&#34;https://rcpmag.com/articles/2021/03/16/what-happened-azure-ad-outage.aspx&#34;&gt;major Azure Active Directory outage&lt;/a&gt; back in March 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A great deal of services were degraded while I was at work so I mostly spent March 15th, 2021 monitoring the situation and broadcasting status updates for fellow affected teams internally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the updates were just synthesised from Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s various Twitter accounts which happened to be more up to date than the public status pages, but that&amp;rsquo;s a story for another blog post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Towards the end of the day, it got me wondering how widely Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s own services were affected by this outage. I mean, they dogfood their product offerings after all, right? Apparently Sales doesn&amp;rsquo;t, at least for any incoming enquiries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you go to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/services/active-directory/&#34;&gt;marketing site for Azure Active Directory&lt;/a&gt;, you may notice a little &amp;ldquo;Chat with Sales&amp;rdquo; tab appear in the bottom right hand corner after all of the various scripts have loaded in the background.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clicking on that tab reveals an &lt;a href=&#34;https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/services/bot-services/&#34;&gt;Azure Chatbot&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;ll ask you which type of help you&amp;rsquo;d like and then you can select one of the follow categories:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Technical support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Business support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sales&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I captured some footage following the dialogue path of these three options during the ongoing Azure AD outage so let&amp;rsquo;s see what happens when selecting each of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;technical-support&#34;&gt;Technical Support&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;You might imagine that this would be the most important option when it comes to resiliency during any major outages. Of course, if you&amp;rsquo;re an enterprise then you should really have an enterprise support plan but if you&amp;rsquo;re a startup or an indie, this might be well outside your budget.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;video style=&#34;display: inherit; margin: 0 auto;&#34; width=&#34;50%&#34; controls&gt;
&lt;source preload src=&#34;01-technical.mp4&#34; type=&#34;video/mp4&#34;&gt;
Ah, sorry! It looks like your browser either hates the h264 codec or it just doesn&#39;t support the video tag.
&lt;/video&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hmm, I don&amp;rsquo;t know about you but it looked like nothing happened and our request just disappeared into the ether!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;business-support&#34;&gt;Business Support&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now surely if a technical person can&amp;rsquo;t get through, business support is much more likely to make it. Nothing says importance like an executive with a credit card after all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;video style=&#34;display: inherit; margin: 0 auto;&#34; width=&#34;50%&#34; controls&gt;
&lt;source preload src=&#34;02-business.mp4&#34; type=&#34;video/mp4&#34;&gt;
Ah, sorry! It looks like your browser either hates the h264 codec or it just doesn&#39;t support the video tag.
&lt;/video&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No dice, basically the same exact outcome. I expected better! Pssh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;sales&#34;&gt;Sales&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now we know for sure that Sales isn&amp;rsquo;t going to work if the former two aren&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In any sane business, all attention should be directed towards supporting paying customers and alleviating any of their concerns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;d be ridiculous to focus on some potentially unrealised future revenues!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;video style=&#34;display: inherit; margin: 0 auto;&#34; width=&#34;50%&#34; controls&gt;
&lt;source preload src=&#34;03-sales.mp4&#34; type=&#34;video/mp4&#34;&gt;
Ah, sorry! It looks like your browser either hates the h264 codec or it just doesn&#39;t support the video tag.
&lt;/video&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hmm, perhaps I was wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-it-supposed-to-look-like&#34;&gt;What is it supposed to look like?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I actually went through this same dialog flow, now two months down the track, and I was under the impression that all three options put you into a live call.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems that both Technical and Business Support options simply redirect you to &lt;a href=&#34;https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/support/create-ticket/&#34;&gt;submit a support ticket&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That makes sense but it also begs the question &amp;ldquo;How was this unavailable?&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presumably the bot is querying for the support ticket URL in some backend every time you click on the button or something equally unnecessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had a quick poke around the acres of websocket events using the developer tools in my browser but there are like 5 events fired off just from clicking a button. It seemed like it was going to be a mess to dig through so I didn&amp;rsquo;t even bother.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, there&amp;rsquo;s an old adage that&amp;rsquo;s probably relevant here. I don&amp;rsquo;t actually know how it goes but basically, if you ever need to get a hold of someone at a company, just call the Sales department because they always pick up the phone.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Will we ever get solid systems?</title>
      <link>https://utf9k.net/blog/solid-systems/</link>
      <description>Is software reliable? Probably not</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
      <author><name>Marcus Crane</name></author>
      <guid>https://utf9k.net/blog/solid-systems/</guid>
      <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;If I had a crystal ball in front of me, one of the things I would like to ask is &amp;ldquo;Will we, the human race, ever get solid systems?&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t mean &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SOLID&#34;&gt;SOLID&lt;/a&gt;, I don&amp;rsquo;t even know what that means, but you know, robust and just generally not prone to letting the user fall right through the cracks by taking an unexpected route.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can think of a couple of examples from the past month or so but they&amp;rsquo;re purely anecdotal of course. There are plenty of great systems that work 99.99% of the time, like &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/EFTPOS&#34;&gt;EFTPOS&lt;/a&gt; or the toilet in my bathroom but I also don&amp;rsquo;t know how you would even go about using such a thing in a way that breaks it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, that&amp;rsquo;s not really my point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just recently, I bought a delivery saver coupon from my local supermarket. It means that I can get as many deliveries as I want during a 3 month period and I don&amp;rsquo;t have to pay a delivery fee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That seems pretty straight forward and I&amp;rsquo;d been meaning to buy one so I thought, why not. I&amp;rsquo;ll buy one and then I&amp;rsquo;ll use it on my next grocery order.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It exists just like any item on the store website so I added it to my cart. I was being lazy and didn&amp;rsquo;t want to expend the mental energy on thinking what to buy so I just got that for now since I&amp;rsquo;d get to use it shortly. It&amp;rsquo;d be silly to buy it only to have to wait for my next order to get the discount anyway, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I added it to my cart and then it asked me if I wanted it delivered or if I wanted to pick it up in store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, that&amp;rsquo;s a bit of a strange question. Isn&amp;rsquo;t it just a coupon code? Ah, I bet it&amp;rsquo;s just a bit of a hack and they have a service at the end which emails me the coupon code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t want to cause any undue trouble, and it&amp;rsquo;s more hassle for me to receive a delivery in the first place so I chose to pick it up at 8am on a Tuesday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got my confirmation sure enough and&amp;hellip; no code. That&amp;rsquo;s weird and I can&amp;rsquo;t find the coupon code input either but ah, it&amp;rsquo;ll probably arrive in a bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tuesday rolls around, and I had since forgotten I had bought the code (I&amp;rsquo;m really bad at procrastinating my grocery orders) and I get a text message saying my order is ready to pick up in store. Great, I guess I&amp;rsquo;ll go over there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, one staff member checked all of the customer pick up lockers and there was no dice. Next, they said they&amp;rsquo;d try and well, I think the assumption was that this was something perhaps to be printed out in the back office? I figured maybe it was something like gift card but no one really seemed to know what form this actual delivery saver took.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A third staff member went out back and after about 10 minutes, they returned with a copy of the receipt and no coupon code. It turns out that despite there being an item, just like any other item on the store website, there&amp;rsquo;s nothing to actually retrieve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead, it&amp;rsquo;s more like an account flag that signifies to the order picker to scan a barcode, from a sheet of barcodes they have at their back desk, and that applies the delivery discount.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That would have been nice to know beforehand. The downfall here I suppose is that I had expected this item to operate just as any other item would in that it represents an asset whether it be a physical item or a digital barcode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my defense however, the system in question still treated it like any other item by creating an order, forwarding that order to someone to go and &amp;ldquo;prepare&amp;rdquo; and then causing trouble for the staff members who were confused.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What likely happened is that whoever entered this item into the system made the assumption that it would always be bundled as part of an order. I wonder if anyone considered the possibility of just buying that item by itself. Worse yet, I bet if I had requested a delivery, a truck would still have stopped by my house with the driver unsure what was actually requested.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fact that you could arguably induce confusion (and pollution) by using an ordering system incorrectly is borderline insanity but one that we live with daily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a similar note, I had recently booked a doctors appointment online for a late Monday morning. Before Monday came around, I had received an SMS telling me that the doctor didn&amp;rsquo;t work Monday and that they had cancelled my appointment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, that seems like an odd way to treat your patients but sure, I get it. Secondly, why is scheduling so hard?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I dislike nothing more than invoking the current year, as if that is any sort of claim to having made progress. Having existed for X number of years doesn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily mean we&amp;rsquo;ve collectively progressed in any meaningful way. I bet you the Greeks were no better at scheduling that we were for sure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next step was to book a new appointment but how am I supposed to know if that won&amp;rsquo;t get cancelled either? How can I have any faith in a system that lets me book timeslots that don&amp;rsquo;t exist? This isn&amp;rsquo;t the first time it has happened before either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For all the time and money that employers spent on having to pay workers less and get more out of their existing cost, it baffles me to no end that they would let employees spend god only knows how many hours a year having to deal with systems that let you do things that should be invalid but still pass validation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, is anything I&amp;rsquo;ve said so far actionable? No&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are we going to get solid, reliable systems and finally see the light as a society? Definitely not&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the biggest issue I imagine is just a general lack of feedback, in a system sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If there is only one cashier overseeing the self checkout area, and 4 people have been blocked by the &amp;ldquo;Nice alcohol. Are you over 18?&amp;rdquo; prompt, followed by another person who wants their package then that&amp;rsquo;s not a good system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clearly it&amp;rsquo;s heavily bottlenecked and there should be more staff, yes but the only inputs I get are doing nothing (still a choice) or getting shitty with the attendant hoping that it escalates my situation up to the top of their work queue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neither of those options have any lasting effect, or even make it into a review of how the system operates, which is barely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I don&amp;rsquo;t know who works on these sorts of customer facing bits of software but a little QA wouldn&amp;rsquo;t go amiss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Better yet, get a bunch of kids to use your system and ask them if they can try and break it. I feel like they&amp;rsquo;d be better at imagining all of the silly permutations like &amp;ldquo;I want a cheeseburger with no cheese, no patty and no bun&amp;rdquo;, which is a very real thing you can order at a McDonalds self service. It&amp;rsquo;ll still cost you the price of a cheeseburger but it&amp;rsquo;s more than worth it watching the ordering system (ie fry cooks) be uttly baffled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, it has no economic impact on anyone above the ground floor. Why can&amp;rsquo;t there be loopholes like this for hedge funds. That&amp;rsquo;d be cool to watch seize up for a little bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, a bit of irony. The store in question was testing out a new &amp;ldquo;Scan and go&amp;rdquo; system. The idea is you scan all of your items and go. The execution fell apart though because one couple needed a supervisor to sign off on their purchase. Maybe they had bought wine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They ended up waiting there for a good five minutes while the attendant had to balanced between some guy buying like 10 bottles of cordial, 2 people waiting for alcohol checks (one of which was me, perhaps to no ones surprise) and said couple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So much for scan and go.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
